<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jon.IO</title><link href="http://jon.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jon.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jon.io/</id><updated>2013-09-03T00:16:21+02:00</updated><entry><title>I am your Nemesis</title><link href="http://jon.io/i-am-your-nemesis.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-03T00:16:21+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2013-09-03:i-am-your-nemesis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi. I'm your competition &amp;amp; whether you like it or not, you're being compared to me and guys like me. I don't have noticeable flaws, emotional hangups, or needy tendencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you are playing video games, I am out running and doing sports. While you're picking out your outfit, I'm doing crunches so I can take my clothes off. While you're at your job, I'm at my career. While you're hanging in your parents basement, I'm traveling around the world. While you're questioning whether or not she likes you, I've already found out. When you're pining over the one that got away, I'm making her laugh but walking away because she's not that interesting. And the worst part is, you probably hold women in higher regard than I do, and treat them with more respect, care, and kindness than I ever have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you hate me? &lt;strong&gt;You should&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I'm the guy she wishes your text was from. I'm the guy that makes you feel 2 inches tall. I'm the reason that women have their emotions guarded, and I'm the guy you'd punch out if you weren't such a little bitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't find enough motivation to change your life just by thinking about all the beautiful ladies you don't know yet, you can find that motivation by thinking about me, messing around with the feelings of the love of your life and then not calling her. You've got to be better, work harder, and do more to be her hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or you can just skip your workout today, stay home tonight &amp;amp; jerk off. Please do, because that makes it so much easier for me and all the other assholes like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am your Nemesis.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="motivation"></category></entry><entry><title>Mapping and processing data in Clojure</title><link href="http://jon.io/mapping-and-processing-data-in-clojure.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-03T00:08:11+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2013-09-03:mapping-and-processing-data-in-clojure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I have a thing for DSLs. You can see it at &lt;a href="https://github.com/jonromero/music-as-data"&gt;music-as-data&lt;/a&gt; were notes and rhythm/beat is "mapped" to data and you can apply data transformations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing I want to do with &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_at_Rest"&gt;data at-rest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a scenario:
I have lots of data sitting as CSV on my hard-drive and I want to process them. Not query them. Process them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would be really interesting is to be able to define (dynamically) a schema like that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;defschema&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;EURUSD&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;tokenizer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;.split&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class="c1"&gt;;; the mapping is done here&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;columns&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;high&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;low&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;volume&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let me explain.
First of all, a "tokenize" function. Each dataline is tokenized based on a function. Do you want regex? Something more complex? You are free to write anything you like. I really hate frameworks that you must write a complex regular expression or use a compicated system just to tokenize a line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, tokenize returns a list of data that are mapped to "columns".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the interesting stuff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can write scripts like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;1.45&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;place-order&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:buy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;place-order&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:sell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Thoughts? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ping me here -&amp;gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/jonromero"&gt;JR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="databases"></category><category term="clojure"></category></entry><entry><title>HybrisDB</title><link href="http://jon.io/hybrisdb.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-04T20:31:21+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2013-08-04:hybrisdb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love Forex because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has enormous amount of data (volume)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These data are coming extremely fast (velocity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to consider multiple resources when you are building your strategy (variety)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My definition of BigData is that you have volume-velocity-variety information &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; you need to react on it right now (realtime). It is one of the main reasons why I don't like Hadoop (ok, the other is because I don't like Java:). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forex is the best place if you want to start playing with BigData. You have (at least) one data channel, hitting you with data, you need to keep running algorithms on this stream (sometimes doing correlations up to a week) and you need be able to respond very fast. If a garbage collector kicks in or if you need to grab data from a database (even if this DB is in memory - long live Redis) then you will have issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the reason why most of the "trading" databases have all their data in the same memory space and have custom languages doing the analysis (like &lt;a href="http://kx.com"&gt;Kdb&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the inspiration for LDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millions of data sources (mobile phones), hitting your database and calculating/updating for each one of the requests thousands of counters and running all sorts of algorithms. Per request. In realtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let's face it. The vast majority of users/companies will never have millions (or even thousands) of requests hitting their servers. That's why I started a new opensource database with codename: HybrisDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HDB has the following characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple to install (no moving parts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple to use (pre-defined dashboards)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It will be perfect for the 99% of users/companies but not for the 1% like Facebook or Google (sacrificing Enterprise features)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is to have a dashboard, to watch indicators going on/off and then (maybe) connect to a system to place an order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like an interesting cool hobby project and I still try to decide between using Erlang or Clojure for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ping me on &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/jonromero"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you have any ideas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JR&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="databases"></category><category term="hybrisdb"></category></entry><entry><title>New blog!</title><link href="http://jon.io/new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-31T00:49:33+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2013-07-31:new-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven't blogged for a while and I think that I needed I new (virtual) home for my rants.
This place is brand new (and white!) and it is going to be awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what will happen with my previous domain (&lt;a href="http://jon.is.emotionull.com"&gt;emotionull&lt;/a&gt;) but I think it might be the new home for a new (underground) social network for traders. We'll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hobby project right now, is a new opensource trading platform (for the first time not focused on HFT) and some experiments around a super fast, vertical scaling, full adhoc queries database (exactly the opposite of &lt;a href="http://www.bugsense.com/about/bigdata"&gt;LDB&lt;/a&gt; I've built at &lt;a href="http://www.bugsense.com"&gt;BugSense&lt;/a&gt;). I'll keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JR&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="intro"></category></entry></feed>