<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jon.IO - Crypto</title><link href="http://jon.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jon.io/feeds/crypto.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jon.io/</id><updated>2022-05-19T09:41:16-07:00</updated><entry><title>Five reasons why you cannot sell your NFTs</title><link href="http://jon.io/five-reasons-why-you-cannot-sell-your-nfts" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-20T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-05-19T09:41:16-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-10-20:/five-reasons-why-you-cannot-sell-your-nfts</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five months ago, I decided to sell my first NFT, &lt;a href="my-birthday-cake-as-an-nft"&gt;a piece of cake for my birthday&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com/"&gt;my NFT platform&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, I sold more than 100 NFTs, sometimes for celebrities, other times for smaller creators or for &lt;a href="https://jon.io/i-organized-my-own-conference-like-gary-vee-in-30-days"&gt;my own conference&lt;/a&gt; (which sold out three times).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five months ago, I decided to sell my first NFT, &lt;a href="my-birthday-cake-as-an-nft"&gt;a piece of cake for my birthday&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com/"&gt;my NFT platform&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, I sold more than 100 NFTs, sometimes for celebrities, other times for smaller creators or for &lt;a href="https://jon.io/i-organized-my-own-conference-like-gary-vee-in-30-days"&gt;my own conference&lt;/a&gt; (which sold out three times).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked with every big Hollywood talent agency and I saw them selling less than my birthday cake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="images/nft-post-sale.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the reasons why they (and you) fail to sell your NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You think the platform matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to Amazon, do you go and browse their homepage to find what is new or are you searching for something specific?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is exactly&lt;/strong&gt; how people buy NFTs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don't go to OpenSea and say "oh this little monkey from a creator I never heard of before is on sale for 10 Ether, I need to buy this right now". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;99% of NFT sales happen by sending people &lt;strong&gt;directly&lt;/strong&gt; to the NFT page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have higher chances of selling NFTs &lt;strong&gt;outside&lt;/strong&gt; of OpenSea/Rarible/etc as your buyers won't get distracted by random NFTs. 
See all projects that make &lt;strong&gt;consistent&lt;/strong&gt; sales. CryptoPunks, &lt;a href="i-bought-this-image-for-1500-and-i-sold-it-for-50-in-two-weeks"&gt;Hashmasks&lt;/a&gt;, Mekaverse - all of the big NFT projects have custom pages for their drops. Of course, if you want to resell you need to end up on OpenSea but don't be delusional thinking that anyone could find your NFT in this (well) sea of NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you would have known that but ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You haven't bought any NFTs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to buy NFTs to understand how to sell NFTs. I met artists with millions of followers that wanted to sell NFTs and didn't have a Metamask wallet. Guess how many NFTs they sold? &lt;strong&gt;Less than my birthday cake&lt;/strong&gt; - and usually &lt;em&gt;zero&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single NFT I bought was because someone from my community recommended that I should check it out. And all NFTs that made me money where bought outside of OpenSea (ok, I made some Ether by &lt;a href="i-bought-this-image-for-1500-and-i-sold-it-for-50-in-two-weeks"&gt;trading on OpenSea&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, trying to sell NFTs without ever buying one is like trying to be a soccer coach without knowing soccer (Ted Lasso is the exception. Also he is a fictional character). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not saying go and spend all your money buying random NFTs. But you need to get involved in projects and communities, see how things work and understand how and why people make money and why you end up having only 4 views of your profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest example is influencers trying to sell to their followers and end up making only "pocket money" because their followers have NO idea how to setup a wallet or what Ether is. I guarantee you the biggest talent agencies with their infinite connections and budgets have ZERO idea how to make any NFT sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having more followers or being famous means shit in the Metaverse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to the next reason on why no one buys your stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You have no Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are following me on &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/jonvictory/"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;, you know by now that I am a true Metallica fan. I am the person who drove 4 hours to go and watch Metallica perform in a Drive-in. I am a &lt;strong&gt;true fan&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community is the biggest asset any creator or company has. It cannot be copied. It cannot be stopped. It cannot be bought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followers are not Believers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The random integers you see on your social profiles that represent how many "followers" you have are just a vanity metric. How many of them are actually going to &lt;strong&gt;travel&lt;/strong&gt; to see you? How many share your values?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sell NFTs (and sell consistently) you need people to share your values. An excellent example is &lt;a href="https://www.supernfty.com/"&gt;SuperNfty&lt;/a&gt;, an amazing creator that has a very active community. You should try and copy something that is true and sustainable. No one became Metallica in a day (or Justin Bieber if that's your thing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll do another post about how to build and maintain your community because there is so much stuff and tools to cover in just one post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let's move to my favorite reason:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Price&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the creators I met, have no idea how much they should price their first NFTs at. They go from 100 Ether (seriously) to zero and end up not 
making any sales. These creators are usually the same people that call NFTs a scam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want me to tell you the price of your NFT? I don't even need to see it. It is zero. Yes, zero Ether. You put the work to create something but you haven't put the work to &lt;strong&gt;honor your community&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead you are trying to rip them off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want people to buy your stuff, you need make sure that your NFTs are 10x more valuable than you price them. If your NFTs have no value (because no one knows who you are or your vision) then you are doing a disservice to your believers (you see? - I didn't say followers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If people can't make money by buying and selling your NFTs you will never survive in this space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trying to sell on a different chain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you made zero sales on the Ethereum blockchain, you decided to go to Solana. Slow clap. I admire your Entrepreneurial spirit but no. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build value, serve your belivers. Stop saying bullshit to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because I might have been too harsh on you already, here are two extra reasons: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You are a famous "traditional" artist so you should make an NFT of your art&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Just no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You are a photographer and have an interesting photo to sell.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: Selling your first NFT, step by step&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Crypto"></category><category term="popular"></category></entry><entry><title>Create 1000 NFT tickets for free in less than 1 minute</title><link href="http://jon.io/create-1000-nft-tickets-for-free-in-less-than-1-minute" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-27T11:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-05-19T09:41:16-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-07-27:/create-1000-nft-tickets-for-free-in-less-than-1-minute</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2021 a crypto event took place in Miami: Bitcoin 2021. One thing that stood out to me
was that the tickets were not available for purchase with Bitcoin or any other cryptocurrency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided for my annual conference &lt;a href="https://jon.io/metaverse2021"&gt;"V as in MetaVerse"&lt;/a&gt; to use NFTs as tickets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2021 a crypto event took place in Miami: Bitcoin 2021. One thing that stood out to me
was that the tickets were not available for purchase with Bitcoin or any other cryptocurrency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided for my annual conference &lt;a href="https://jon.io/metaverse2021"&gt;"V as in MetaVerse"&lt;/a&gt; to use NFTs as tickets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial I will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaimg.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you can create as many NFT tickets as your want &lt;strong&gt;for free&lt;/strong&gt;. The NFT tickets are 100% NFTs (ERC721), stored in IPFS and are available automatically on OpenSea after someone buys them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you won't need any special software to "check-in" people - just a phone camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you can charge and get paid in Ether for your event just by entering your wallet address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you can create a &lt;strong&gt;mailing list&lt;/strong&gt; of everyone who bought your NFT ticket (and make support super easy).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you won't learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to change the image of the NFT (and text) after someone checked-in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to airdrop NFT gifts to your buyers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use the API to create a service to sell tickets.
I'll cover all of this in the next tutorial - so don't forget to subscribe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn about the first Metaverse conference that used this technology - you can read &lt;a href=""&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How can I create NFT tickets?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating NFT tickets is as easy as creating simple NFTs. It is just one checkbox. One click. Right here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/clicknft.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let's go into detail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating an NFT on &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com"&gt;OMGDrops.com&lt;/a&gt; assumes that you have an approved creator's account. If you don't, drop by the &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/eNWGH9GSMX"&gt;discord&lt;/a&gt; and I'll create one for you. Sorry we are a small team and we are trying not to drown in support requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, you don't need ANY money to create NFTs. No need for Ether either. You can have a zero balance crypto wallet. No need to pay for proxies (I am looking at you, OpenSea) or to mint an NFT (I am looking at you, Rarible). Your buyers can buy your NFTs in pure Ether (no need to convert to WETH, DAI or whatever) and at the lowest gas fees out there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/buy.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let's see how really easy it is to create an NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/upload_nft_high.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You upload your image/gif/movie whatever, write a small description and then you click &lt;strong&gt;unlockable content&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;NFT ticket&lt;/strong&gt;. You press "Done" and well ... you are done! Everyone can buy your sparkling, awesome, majestic NFT for your brilliant event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What happens after someone buys the NFT ticket?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone buys your NFT ticket, it becomes immediatelly available on OpenSea for trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/opensea.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means the buyer can put it on auction, fixed price or do whatever else they want. Oh, and you always get to keep 10% of the resale price ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can also "unlock it" by clicking "unlock content" and putting their email - they will get a QR code. This QR can be used to check in at the event but more importantly it can be saved as an image, so the buyer won't need internet access at check-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/unlock.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People at the check-in door have a couple of choices to scan the tickets. The easiest is with a phone camera. They will be redirected to a page that says whether the ticket is &lt;strong&gt;valid&lt;/strong&gt;, has been &lt;strong&gt;resold&lt;/strong&gt; or has been &lt;strong&gt;redeemed&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next choice (which is my favorite) is using the scanner from a cryptowallet. In that case, the door scanner can "check in" the user (so noone else can use the ticket). The scanner or the issuer can also change any metadata including the NFT image - we call these dynamic NFTs. I will cover this in the next blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metacheck.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, all NFTs with unlockable content require email address of the buyer, so you can integrate this with your CRM (still unsure whether we are going to keep this feature).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's recap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You created your tickets &lt;strong&gt;for free&lt;/strong&gt; in 5 seconds and they are even &lt;a href="/images/ipfs.gif"&gt;automatically stored on IPFS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You checked in everyone securely without going crazy and without any special software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have their wallet addresses in case you want to airdrop them any free NFTs (as a thank you).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You created a mailing list with your NFT buyers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to play around and break the system - feel free to jump to our &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/eNWGH9GSMX"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;. I will be more than happy to see this solution used for all real crypto events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: We also have an API if you are interested in building your own first NFT ticketing platform!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: Using the API to create as many NFTs as you want.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Crypto"></category><category term="popular"></category></entry><entry><title>How NFTs will change events (and why Mark Cuban is a genius)?</title><link href="http://jon.io/how-nfts-will-change-events-and-why-mark-cuban-is-a-genius" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-06T11:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-05-19T09:41:16-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-06-06:/how-nfts-will-change-events-and-why-mark-cuban-is-a-genius</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Your friend Cathrine &lt;strong&gt;loves&lt;/strong&gt; The Dallas Mavericks and she got you some tickets! Hooray! But deep down you are really a Lakers fan 
and you don't really want to go but the ticket was kind of expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Cathrine for being such a good friend and getting me a …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Your friend Cathrine &lt;strong&gt;loves&lt;/strong&gt; The Dallas Mavericks and she got you some tickets! Hooray! But deep down you are really a Lakers fan 
and you don't really want to go but the ticket was kind of expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Cathrine for being such a good friend and getting me a courtside seat ticket that costs &lt;strong&gt;a fortune&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="images/ticket-red.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your alternative is to try to sell it (and maybe less than she got it for) and try not to get scammed (or knifed) while selling it. So much stress for having good friends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter NFT Tickets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But fortunately your ticket was actually an NFT ticket. That means that you can sell it on one of the existing platforms pretty easily and probably &lt;strong&gt;at a higher&lt;/strong&gt; price. If everything goes as planned, you should be able to sell it under a minute or even put it up for an auction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Cathrine is devastated that you want to sell her gift (and make a profit off of it). So you decide to go to the event.
And it is actually pretty fun! The check-in is like a normal ticket with a QR code but what is epic is that the DallasM  has "airdropped" (lingo for sending you for free) a new NFT that unlocks a hoodie. BOOM! Oh and now you have access to the highlights of the show! And you can sell your &lt;strong&gt;collectible&lt;/strong&gt; ticket after the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This.is.awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why NFT tickets are the future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is one utility to NFTs, it the ability to resale your tickets without having to jump through hoops or pay crazy fees. And I know this could be a heaven for scalpers (and hell for everyone else) but bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I buy my ticket &lt;strong&gt;with Ether&lt;/strong&gt; for Dallas Maverics vs LA Lakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can resell the ticket if I want to and the team gets a cut from resales - because that's how NFTs work (and blacklist scalpers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I check-in with my ticket without any complicated apps &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can get more NFTs as airdrops if Dallas win (and I can keep them as memorabilia or sell them)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My NFT ticket can also change after the game - for example to reflect the score (see later on: dynamic NFTs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why NFT tickets are NOT the future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets &lt;strong&gt;must be bought and sold&lt;/strong&gt; with Ether and that means some initial friction. I've seen tons of new NFT platforms and NFT ticketing solutions that are destined to crash and burn because they plan to sell NFTs with fiat ($ or euro). Why fiat sucks? Because if you really want to participate in selling your NFTs, stacking them up, unlocking content and doing all these crazy stuff in the Metaverse &lt;strong&gt;you need to be on the blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;. If I am just an entry in your database and I am not really the owner of my NFT &lt;strong&gt;why are we doing  this&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, after the initial friction of setting up a metamask wallet, users that bought my &lt;a href="i-organized-my-own-conference-like-gary-vee-in-30-days"&gt;NFT tickets for my conference&lt;/a&gt; were able to immediately resell them in a HUGE market (OpenSea) or use them to unlock videos from the conference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being "on the chain" is hands down the best long term experience. Unless you don't want people to resale your NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's it. That's the only thing. I used NFT tickets for my conference and almost 1000 new wallets were created by people who haven't heard about NFTs before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not rocket science and this is how you grow your community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested to learn how ridunkulously easy it is to create your NFT tickets in a jiffy (what a strange word &lt;strong&gt;jiffy&lt;/strong&gt; is), &lt;a href="create-1000-nft-tickets-for-free-in-less-than-1-minute"&gt;check this post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send me an email if you want to exchange any ideas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: Using the API to create as many NFTs as you want&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Crypto"></category><category term="popular"></category></entry></feed>