<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jon.IO - Newsletters</title><link href="http://jon.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jon.io/feeds/newsletters.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jon.io/</id><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><entry><title>Robots don’t care how rich you are and how safe your job really is</title><link href="http://jon.io/robots-dont-care-how-rich-you-are-and-how-safe-your-job-really-is" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-10T22:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-12-10:/robots-dont-care-how-rich-you-are-and-how-safe-your-job-really-is</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go with the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Yesterday I gave a talk in &lt;a href="https://decentraland.org/"&gt;Decentraland&lt;/a&gt; about DAOs, &lt;a href="https://www.citydao.io/"&gt;CityDAO&lt;/a&gt; and the future …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go with the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Yesterday I gave a talk in &lt;a href="https://decentraland.org/"&gt;Decentraland&lt;/a&gt; about DAOs, &lt;a href="https://www.citydao.io/"&gt;CityDAO&lt;/a&gt; and the future of DAOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/oiaot0WcxrdulBUs3XRimSfJtxzhsPYrEIqMhMsp16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that's my avatar in the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn't manage to attend (probably because you are not following me on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jonromero"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/jonvictory/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;) the highlights were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a strong cause behind what you do, people will join and help. It is not just about the money
Mistakes are bound to happen but as long as you made an informed decision, it is ok. You cannot predict the future and take into account unknown variables
Try to scale slowly. Going viral is most of the times a curse
Beware of the scammers. So many of them in the crypto space&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ I posted a couple of weeks ago about a DAO that we are building. We have a name (KaramelaDAO) and a vibrant community that is operating semi-autonomously. We do at least two community calls per week so if you are interested in learning more about DAOs, the Metaverse and how we can take over a Greek Island and elected our own representative, &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/ePSSJdzfqA"&gt;drop by our Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/karameladao"&gt;DAO on Twitter too&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ The last couple of weeks, I keep hearing that working for a Web3 company is "dangerous". You can always be replaced on the spot or the company can fail and/or run out of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me introduce you to Better.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better.com is a well funded company that has 1 billion dollars and last week the &lt;a href="https://amp.cnn.com/cnn/2021/12/08/business/better-executive-resignations/index.html"&gt;CEO fired 900 people during a Zoom call&lt;/a&gt;. On the spot. Like, hey Merry Christmas for those that are not on this call because &lt;strong&gt;YOU&lt;/strong&gt; are fired. No reason. No explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least in a DAO you get to keep your governance token and vote rights and kinda know about these kind of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ Oh Elon Elon Elon. At first you loved getting government money to build cool stuff but the moment the word "union" was heard you started thrashing around about inflation and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1468684576407101440"&gt;about the incentives other companies get to also build cool stuff&lt;/a&gt;. But that's ok. I still love you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I want to believe that money and resourcefulness solve everything but it seems that &lt;a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/neuralink-tesla-have-an-ai-problem-elons-money-cant-solve"&gt;A.I needs something more than money&lt;/a&gt; and that means that we won't get &lt;a href="https://neuralink.com/"&gt;Neuralink&lt;/a&gt; any time soon or self-driving cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But weirdest things have happened so who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ Talking about weird stuff, I always found super strange that whenever Christies was selling some SUPER expensive multimillion NFT, there was always something fishy happening (sales not recorded on the blockchain, no open prices etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And behold, Christie decided to do some &lt;a href="https://www.artnews.com/art-news/market/christies-opensea-nft-sale-1234612759/amp/"&gt;sales directly on the blockchain&lt;/a&gt; and ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it wasn't that impressive. At all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFTs were accused of being the perfect tool for money laundering but maybe there &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/opensea-admits-incident-as-top-exec-is-accused-of-trading-nfts-on-insider-information/"&gt;are more transparent that normal companies&lt;/a&gt; because of the huge community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all for this week, see you next week with possibly a surprise ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>Mr Beast is a beast and the crypto domination continues</title><link href="http://jon.io/mr-beast-is-a-beast-and-the-crypto-domination-continues" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-02T22:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-12-02:/mr-beast-is-a-beast-and-the-crypto-domination-continues</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go with the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ It has become a tradition by now, to have one &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; thing happening …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go with the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ It has become a tradition by now, to have one &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; thing happening in the DAO space every week. This is the &lt;a href="https://jon.io/how-to-win-without-talent-making-money-and-metaverse-cities"&gt;fourth newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and trust me on this, I am not even talking about 1/64 of what is happening out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started helping out &lt;a href="https://www.citydao.io/"&gt;CityDAO&lt;/a&gt; with their Constitution smart contract and just like that I started another DAO, called DAOCracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of people helping out already, we had two community calls and I love it! If you want to participate and learn about web3, NFTs, the metaverse and how to work for a DAO, drop by our &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/ePSSJdzfqA"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; (channel #the-dao). I promise you, this DAO is for new people to learn more about this crazy new space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ In the meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/22/el-salvador-plans-bitcoin-city-raise-1-billion-via-bitcoin-bond.html"&gt;El Salvador decided to create a "Bitcoin City"&lt;/a&gt; and raise $1 billion via "Bitcoin Bond". Translation: &lt;strong&gt;Scam&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no city being build that is not on the Ethereum blockchain and not using NFTs. Building a Bitcoin City makes as much sense as building a city using rocks. You can do it but you are probably an idiot. In this case, you cannot even build a city with Bitcoin as you cannot do any transactions and there are no smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ And we are back with our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tH-ZrHCkXzo"&gt;weekly pitch deck reviews&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I am reviewing a pretty solid Startup, with a very impressive technology. If I could change only one thing in their pitch deck that would be ... (come on, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RXduZ4VdXCs"&gt;watch the video&lt;/a&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you haven't subscribed to the channel, &lt;strong&gt;DO IT NOW&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/hodzT9gEL9Ep5E2YVegFMT2GzrWiuZKqE1OA2SsY16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RXduZ4VdXCs"&gt;Click here to see this epic video!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ If you don't know Mr Beast, oh you are in for a surprise. An excellent creator, that creates super viral videos. His last video is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0e3GPea1Tyg"&gt;Squid Games&lt;/a&gt;. 135 Million views in 7 days. Yes, he had more viewers that the actual Squid games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to create viral content, study him (I know I am!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ The founder of Twitter left Twitter. But that's not the big news. Jack Dorsey is also the founder of Square (a huge fintech company) that is now &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/dorsey-led-square-rebrands-block-2021-12-01/"&gt;rebranding to Block&lt;/a&gt;. Yes Block as in &lt;strong&gt;Block&lt;/strong&gt;chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are still working for a web2 company, you have to &lt;strong&gt;immediately&lt;/strong&gt; reevaluate your choices. Join a DAO, and start reading as much as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to have a job in the future, you need to start working for the "future" - someone I don't remember&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>Becoming a genius, robots in preschools and DAOs against hedge funds</title><link href="http://jon.io/becoming-a-genius-robots-in-preschools-and-daos-against-hedge-funds" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-11-24T22:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-11-24:/becoming-a-genius-robots-in-preschools-and-daos-against-hedge-funds</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go with the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ I've been talking DAOs non-stop for the last three newsletters. And for a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go with the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ I've been talking DAOs non-stop for the last three newsletters. And for a good reason because DAOs are the future of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week a &lt;a href="https://www.constitutiondao.com/"&gt;DAO decided to buy a copy of the American Constitution&lt;/a&gt;. They managed to raise $47M &lt;strong&gt;in a week&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790452/constitutiondao-loses-auction-for-rare-us-constitution-copy-sothebys"&gt;They lost the auction&lt;/a&gt; to the founder and CEO of Citadel - one of the biggest hedge funds on the planet. But what does this mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/nvXtnQBggX-LXt8grO2n00LkeJkIYhuPtzMnPk66vLcERh31BYdzIssk9OhZy7QXnDkzIZwEht_utTb79m8GXzGTGCKAZJR_nQ1J63dsesFY84zt0RuyBJAtcOXMlGBu9IReqQ=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/1uIUdxGBQbVrdb55nP8L79fup8QqaLXgEwFL7djN16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAOs can mobilize people (and money) extremely fast - faster than we have ever seen. The reason is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is equal in the DAO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larger companies feel threatened as they cannot retain talented people and are left with those who "play it safe". Every single VC (that worth its salt) has switched to funding "Web3" companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DAOs pay better, are more fun to work with and provide more value than "web 2.0" companies. But of course there are downsides (which we'll talk about next week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ Last week we had a &lt;a href="https://www.citydao.io/"&gt;CityDAO&lt;/a&gt; Los Angeles meetup. And it was epic. There I learnt about &lt;a href="https://mars.college/"&gt;Mars College&lt;/a&gt;, a Burning-Man-For-Hackers playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens there is that for three months, people that are creators, tinkers, thinkers, hackers and want to stretch their mind beyond the social norms, &lt;strong&gt;build a city&lt;/strong&gt;, create study groups and &lt;strong&gt;do deep work&lt;/strong&gt;. In the end of the "college", the city is torn down (like in Burning Man).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to rent a van and visit my friends in February, so if you want to come along just send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ Last week I took a break from reviewing &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tH-ZrHCkXzo"&gt;pitch decks&lt;/a&gt; and I started doing small videos answering questions that came from you. That's what I did again this week (I promise, next week I'll go back to reviewing your pitch decks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/zlzdzjez/zp82yz"&gt;I rant about NDAs&lt;/a&gt; and why you might seem as "not knowing what you are doing" if you ask one from investors. Take a look (it's a 2-minute epic video with Los Angeles as the background).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you haven't subscribed to the channel, &lt;strong&gt;DO IT NOW&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/u0-JWQF3PGk0Cac0LegwXGSyMuN7KUmuoQz7g2fMsaIDEYaLu-e7J3SUt5_q45xlRkGmHNEUHXzojQROquz0xDJt54JpEoOYm-B2NqqPMdd3ndlbv88rpjT7qYdOxGaTbLVX1A=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/5nbwJB2xARLx1IU4hOqzml4nbxDnnErczzZgGn2g16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/zlzdzjez/zp82yz"&gt;Click here to see the epic video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ South Korea is &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/zlzdzjez/jqvxoz"&gt;experimenting with small robots&lt;/a&gt; in pre-schools. Yes, you are in the Kindergarten and you are given a small robot in order to familiarize yourself with the future technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't start saying "when I was in the Kindergarten I used to run all day and play with my friends" because I am not stupid. Offering &lt;strong&gt;more knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;deeper&lt;/strong&gt; understanding gives you an advantage. Like teaching your kids chess. Or a musical instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; more complex than the past. It is just moves faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ I heard many times that I am a talented Entrepreneur, engineer or singer (ok, I've never heard the singer part). And whenever I say that "it is mostly hard work", I get the eyeroll. Here is an interesting story that proves that &lt;strong&gt;you are what you dedicate time on&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, a psychologist decided to see if you are born a (chess) genius or you can become one. And he did what every normal person does: &lt;strong&gt;he put an ad to find a women to bear a child for him&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as all love stories go, he found one. And they had three girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He decided to teach all girls how to play chess. Oh an important part of the story: himself &lt;strong&gt;was not&lt;/strong&gt; a chess prodigy/genius/grandmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short the three girls, without having in their "DNA" the genius chromosome, they became chess prodigies and two of them are the first and second best chess players in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he had a trick to do that. A very simple trick. Deep, non-stop hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time you find excuses, remember that is &lt;strong&gt;all you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/zlzdzjez/2yg52d"&gt;Read the story here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>NFT shoes and some of you are getting free books!</title><link href="http://jon.io/nft-shoes-and-some-of-you-are-getting-free-books" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-11-18T22:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-11-18:/nft-shoes-and-some-of-you-are-getting-free-books</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ The majority of people around us haven't been conditioned into taking action. That's why …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ The majority of people around us haven't been conditioned into taking action. That's why they have a hard time understanding what separates a good decision from a bad one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/yBm865Hw2k3wqSMFQ0D8NuygFzCqZDZ84TZt11dDI5En9D_bQGi51NjOP4fR_NlFwZ62dRcxmmJGa85I3SzRRIIe6NqX-lyfTgPiwUNQT-VHzjsafZBN8l6SmWJRw2pQ3bP6OA=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/vnMHP1cRGbd4BNUq15aUUrfOhTFZlhwd4l7wT2rD16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decision that takes a lot of time will end up in &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/p8ydlv"&gt;Analysis Paralysis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decision that tries to gather all data, it might no longer be beneficial as the landscape moves. Successful investments are done only with 20% of available information - before everybody else finds out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making decisions is more than data/facts collection. It is about &lt;strong&gt;execution&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have this in the back of your mind when you try to find your next move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ Last time I talked about &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/54nlyq"&gt;Crypto Cities&lt;/a&gt; and more specifically about &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/zp70oj"&gt;CityDAO&lt;/a&gt; (disclosure: I am affiliated with CityDAO). A week ago, we were 6000 Citizens planning how to build software to create a new city. This week we are 10k Citizens - and no more Citizens will be accepted at this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I am excited about DAOs is that I am working on launching a new DAO about the Metaverse and Web3. I am looking for names and if you come up with one, you'll get a free "citizenship".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be involved - drop by my &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/p8yd0v"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; and join the channel #TheDao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ This week I took a break from reviewing &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/jq5g8q"&gt;pitch decks&lt;/a&gt; and I started doing small videos answering questions that came from you. &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/xz62rn"&gt;Here is the first one&lt;/a&gt; (and one of my favorites). If you have any questions, reply to this email and I'll (probably) do a small video about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci3.googleusercontent.com/proxy/4LvDNgWCUsEVbLmfkY036dRKIIH3H298WJIXx174HZjPyDCESc_rTw6oSsfEe3LTLa3_OXtvqm9pUd2uONqPtro9UFOIuf4knaYjyG9J1VNlN0cICmF0fGKai5F-lwD0T0fUxA=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/ReCeXGgaIwqpjdk6uZrQXzAnJOJYXVTtrgG40szZ16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/xz62rn"&gt;Click here to see this epic video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ A couple weeks ago, I asked all of you to &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/ll2rvp"&gt;help out with selling the domain house.new&lt;/a&gt;. I have three offers but they are a bit complicated. I'll wait a couple weeks before deciding. If you have a small Startup and you can use the domain, you can get it at a huge discount - just to irritate Zillow, &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/jq5rwq"&gt;that is having a terrible week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ If you are &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/2y9pj6"&gt;watching my videos&lt;/a&gt;, you should know that I include hidden gems for those who are observant. In one of them I said at the end of the video "if you are watching this, I'll send you something interesting".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To everyone that saw the hidden gem and reached out to me, you'll be getting a hardcopy of one of my favorite books "How To Live" that was released a couple months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci3.googleusercontent.com/proxy/nLR9i8AdInH2TfNDo3HMHgThlurpYhQeWV3nHj5Z-G9d0WD7F9A_Uwh-mtXSUYy5kpSGZ_oJ80UPP2E6pWz1QAXMwllCs7pwXw0_CCRtBkKso8Nm0Z2PNfLH_XGj1CG48BoOng=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/keiFw86LVaSRoz4OskC4rTlwZ8UHCgBJhiblCKCk16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I like sending people physical items is that I like having a real connection. When you get a physical item - especially a book - you create conversations and bonds stronger than just words on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as you know, I always respond to anyone that sends me an email - that's why I am doing this newsletter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ I talked about the Metaverse many times and I even had &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/qwpez6"&gt;my own Metaverse conference&lt;/a&gt; last summer but the space is getting crazy hot. Facebook (or should I say Meta?) will &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/k02oly"&gt;release haptic gloves&lt;/a&gt; so we can punch each other, China will &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/jq5req"&gt;integrate Metaverse with reality&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/gve242"&gt;Roblox&lt;/a&gt; (one of my favorite companies - disclosure: I am an investor) went up 30% in a day as more brands wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and Nike is preparing &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/695yoe"&gt;a new Metaverse, NFTs and cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; benefit from this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are experiencing one of the biggest wealth creation events in the human history. It's one of the few times where having deep knowledge of a subject and being able to provide/create value can change your life and the life of thousands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not just "Web-3", it is "Internet-2"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start reading about DAOs, NFTs, how you can participate, how they work, how this new world operates and what are the new rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/580rn0rq/09qx6q"&gt;It is crazy right now but it is going to get crazier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I am reviving the "Algorithms Pay My Bills" Community on &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/ePSSJdzfqA"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, so if you want to drop by and chit-chat, you are more than welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>Owning your own eSports team and building crypto cities</title><link href="http://jon.io/owning-your-own-esports-team-and-building-crypto-cities" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-11-10T22:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-11-10:/owning-your-own-esports-team-and-building-crypto-cities</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Last time I talked about &lt;a href="https://jon.io/how-to-win-without-talent-making-money-and-metaverse-cities"&gt;Metaverse Cities&lt;/a&gt;. What I haven't told you is that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about the Top 5 things that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Last time I talked about &lt;a href="https://jon.io/how-to-win-without-talent-making-money-and-metaverse-cities"&gt;Metaverse Cities&lt;/a&gt;. What I haven't told you is that I am a Citizen of the &lt;a href="https://www.citydao.io/"&gt;CityDAO&lt;/a&gt;. CityDAO has bought real land in Wyoming and a community of 6k+ citizens is planning to build a whole city. Seems that the Metaverse is clashing with reality pretty hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I am excited about DAOs is that I am working on launching a new DAO about the Metaverse and Web3. If you want to be involved - drop by &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/ePSSJdzfqA"&gt;my Discord&lt;/a&gt; and join the channel #TheDao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ In my latest &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/4g26oke7/e84rop"&gt;pitch deck review&lt;/a&gt;, I talk about what most investors look in a pitch deck. Hint: It is money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/RBMqw_0ljR2vHuK2hsfHmkOrLEfWsMAROV74XpCYKeFDZPTzyiLh581dp-0GyP22nPzh49N3t4NObPxFt8hr8MN5wjNhVZmQPPGMH6FbtLEQNQsisbLEeT8SR_CDbSTbjdKD-w=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/6JqdpM2IKdGOqIXCkQDwmQYvpiCdyhdIgDICV3jP16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/4g26oke7/e84rop"&gt;Click here to see this epic video!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ I've invested in a lot of DAOs and "not traditional" companies but one of them will blow your mind with their business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a crypto game called &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/4g26oke7/84204r"&gt;Axie Infinity&lt;/a&gt;, valued at $3 Billion and got funding from the biggest VCs on the planet. To participate in that game you need to buy their NFTs and then by playing you can earn money - this is called Play-to-Earn (P2E).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is mind blowing is that you can invest in a "company" that buys the NFTs and "rents" them out to players in countries like the Philippines. These players play all day long, win money and they "profit-share" with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you still haven't got it, you can have your own e-Sports team, running fully decentralized and autonomously, earning money while you sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/4g26oke7/k0y7qj"&gt;Here is a video to see more about this story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ Netflix is &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/4g26oke7/p8ovgd"&gt;expanding to games&lt;/a&gt;. You will be able to buy and play games using your Netflix subscription. It seems that all companies at the moment became game companies and then add NFTs. I wonder if anyone is still building non-Entertainment products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I am reviving the "Algorithms Pay My Bills" Community on &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/ePSSJdzfqA"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, so if you want to drop by and chit-chat, you are more than welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>How to win without talent, making money and Metaverse cities</title><link href="http://jon.io/how-to-win-without-talent-making-money-and-metaverse-cities" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-11-04T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-11-04:/how-to-win-without-talent-making-money-and-metaverse-cities</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many exciting things happened last week (I won't even discuss about &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/vq6krd"&gt;Facebook changing their name to Meta&lt;/a&gt;) so let's jump right into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ I've …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many exciting things happened last week (I won't even discuss about &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/vq6krd"&gt;Facebook changing their name to Meta&lt;/a&gt;) so let's jump right into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ I've been working towards building a "real" Metaverse. That means a city, with its &lt;strong&gt;own physical language&lt;/strong&gt;, currency and a DAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Αλγοκρατία (Algocracy) is a type of Democracy where instead of Demos (the public) holding (crato/krato) the laws, we have algorithms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the heart of the Metaverse and not 3d avatars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/k0kgdy"&gt;Click here to share it on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it seems that is the next steps as &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/742v6l"&gt;Metacities are started to get formed&lt;/a&gt;. What a crazy world we live in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in helping out, reply to this email and I'll keep you in the loop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/69wwze"&gt;In my latest pitch deck review&lt;/a&gt;, I talk about why you need a CTO and why you shouldn't scale prematurely. As my personal motto goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make it to fail, not to scale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/LxyS5acjdrGtjvJmaHwBPvOXvPJiDmXftTE5S6cMxnjO7kAAgUfIFcQs7Wej8dFTVt7GbHYFHJBou9-zi8nIMngMNvmUDA6DUFVnWHDzLLZPBhJCts83LrHWKanqj0EIhynrYg=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/mafGqKDYXjqj6iDQoJc4Xn33SFM2QAClst5IcVDE16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/69wwze"&gt;Click here to see this epic video!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ The most common misconceptions for success are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) You need to be smart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) You need to be rich&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) You need to be talented&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can guarantee you that if &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/op6649"&gt;someone like me&lt;/a&gt; can do it then everyone can. And I mean it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The things that helped me in building insanely competitive companies, destroying competition, making crazy investments (sometimes with 300x return) or identifying new markets long before the majority (like Ethereum at $8) are these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) You should have no issue with failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to fail = Learn to adapt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Destroy your ego if you want to make a change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/xz0029"&gt;Share this on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) Learn how to become &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/qwnneg"&gt;Antifragile&lt;/a&gt;. It is impossible not to have your ass beaten so learn how to become like water - powerful but never rigid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) Get better at storytelling. If you cannot inspire people, if you cannot make them dream, it doesn't make what you are building. Take lessons, start writing small stories even blog posts and get better at storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d) Commit. Do you want a perfect body? Commit to diet and exercise. Do you want to build wealth? Commit to hard work. Do you want love? Commit to improving yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple but not easy instructions ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ I am planning to release the third version of &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/dpzz70"&gt;OMGDrops&lt;/a&gt;, the NFT Marketplace that I started by accident. But I am going to do this in public!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a movement called #buildinpublic where you build your product "in the open", for everyone to see. You share the good times and the bad times. And I like it because it helps more people to see that Startups are not overnight successes but hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an amazing infographic by &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/84xxl2"&gt;manceraio&lt;/a&gt; that can help you launch your Startup - if you want to try out the #buildinpublic movement ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/oeBR5CoTr340IWYcogZ4RMk9RV84Crf1m4H_ur7zUFqD5Z3y_X5Tvx19Y6f1oMUbZGBV3w3DWhYcR2x7RjsYewB8kMTGKkIgG2fp391kG9Klly3Oy5PKbsiR4br1y0dlFCr11w=s0-d-e1-ft#https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/bW8CwS6KhzdB2n6dGnLXZQZO3udV8gDtnc9oCBA716325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ There is a new kind of domain, the &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/xz00y9"&gt;".new"&lt;/a&gt;. These are called "the shortcuts of the web". For example, if you go to &lt;a href="https://sendfox.com/trk/click/9x5v9g0p/84xxl8"&gt;docs.new&lt;/a&gt;, a new Google Doc will be created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I bought the house.new domain because I think that companies (like Zillow) will love to have this domain. But instead of just selling it, I want to try an experiment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can find a buyer for house.new, you get 20% of the final price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's that simple. You find a buyer (let's say $10k), the buyer gets it and you get $2k (or whatever it is after fees). The highest price by next Thursday, gets the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And this is where things become interesting&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead of me spending these money on surfboards, I will place the money in a DAO that will hire people (maybe you?) to do more tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is that this DAO, becomes self-sustained, grows its capital thus making everyone a shareholder, decision-maker, employee and employer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>Can academics build products?</title><link href="http://jon.io/can-academics-build-products" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-28T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-10-28:/can-academics-build-products</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I posted on LinkedIn a question: What tricks do you know to sell products more efficiently?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/7IbbWPotOF0n3s5JMUwWG8Kwjdie7g2hbt6z4LWi16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some cool comments were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) Never say that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I posted on LinkedIn a question: What tricks do you know to sell products more efficiently?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/7IbbWPotOF0n3s5JMUwWG8Kwjdie7g2hbt6z4LWi16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some cool comments were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) Never say that you are better than a competitor - companies have already done their due diligence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) B2B Software selling, it's 70% side-by-side solution architecture, 20% empathising, and 10% team character. If you reached into the point of the funnel that you have a call/meting, you don't have to "sell".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) Don't freeze or stutter on the cost question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more comments &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/johnvlachoyiannis_one-thing-i-learnt-as-an-entrepreneur-trying-activity-6859087531116494848-kxz7"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and if we are not connected on Linkedin, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnvlachoyiannis/"&gt;we should&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let jump to the top five things that happened last 7 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Today Facebook will be announcing its Metaverse plans. But wait wait wait. If you haven't seen &lt;a href="https://boingboing.net/2021/10/27/watch-facebooks-metaverse-musical-about-open-enrollment-for-benefits.html"&gt;Facebook's official metaverse musical about employees&lt;/a&gt; you are missing out. It is sooo cringeworthy and internet is going nuts about the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ In my &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vS3EXCXkZnY"&gt;latest pitch deck review&lt;/a&gt;, I talk about academics trying to build products and Startups. The video has already created very heated discussions as my point of view is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;building stuff &amp;gt; talking about stuff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this video I talk about why it might hurt your chances raising money if you have taken money for your Startup from a government (or the European union) or why it might be negative if you have any scientific papers about your product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/dFT40SmMpqjZja8nWnRyYh86PIjWTQFJo3jp88Im16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vS3EXCXkZnY"&gt;Click here to see this epic video!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ Having said that, Ryan Petersen put the glasses on every single Operations researcher/scientist in LA and universities got offended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The port of LA/Long Beach is at a standstill. That means shipments are not making their way around California, the US and even the whole world. It is a gridlock, an operational mayhem. What Ryan did? &lt;strong&gt;He rented a boat and inspected the operations as close as he could&lt;/strong&gt;. He identified the easiest thing to fix that would solve 90% of the issue and posted his solution on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When you're designing an operation you must choose your bottleneck. If the bottleneck appears somewhere that you didn't choose it, you aren't running an operation. It's running you."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then people start improving on the idea and shared it with the Mayor of Long Beach, Robert Garcia. &lt;strong&gt;And OMG, it was actually implemented! AND IT WORKS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/DaXp7SlpYFsC4Iqjji5IoqOzvt6Sv8j4UKKixp3D16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ A crypto collective - a DAO - bought from the Department of Justice &lt;a href="https://pleasr.mirror.xyz/PTzSIYe6LbNW55i_Jo4S_fgqIiDp3d7YblpikQ1iRks"&gt;Wu-Tang Clan’s unreleased album&lt;/a&gt;, Once Upon a Time in Shaolin for &lt;strong&gt;$4M&lt;/strong&gt;. Let me break it down for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu-Tang Clan's unreleased album was bought by a hedge fund manager that went to jail for fraud for seven years. Department of Justice got custody of the album. And this is where things become interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/XUTAIVjPcKB0xoV8mwcm9ppXcrLPbKs7EvyJOnO316325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A group of people have formed a DAO to buy collectible NFTs. The name of the DAO is &lt;a href="https://pleasr.org/"&gt;PleasrDAO&lt;/a&gt; and they have bought some very interesting NFTs in the past. Long story short, they went to DOJ and said that we want to buy that album for $4M and ... boom! &lt;strong&gt;They are now the only people on the planet that have heard this album and have the rights&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ The first trillion is always the hardest. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/20/spacex-could-make-elon-musk-world-first-trillionaire-says-morgan-stanley"&gt;Elon Musk is on his way to become the first trillionaire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>What do you know about the Metaverse?</title><link href="http://jon.io/what-do-you-know-about-the-metaverse" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-21T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-10-21:/what-do-you-know-about-the-metaverse</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember all these financial analysts claiming that the internet is a fad, a bubble? How many huge enterprises shutdown for being to stiff to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague or a friend should read them, please get them to sign up on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember all these financial analysts claiming that the internet is a fad, a bubble? How many huge enterprises shutdown for being to stiff to "go with the wave", how many people missed out on a big "wealth transfer event"?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is happening again with the Metaverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can scream and shout that crypto and NFTs are a scam but reality doesn't care about anyone's opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/J1JVxJiGSJb9M733MiPsBKVyDLbE3HoktOB01lfr16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some things you need to know about the "new reality":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse"&gt;Facebook will be changing its name&lt;/a&gt; and will hire more than 10000 people to build the Metaverse (or at least Facebook's version of Metaverse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, Amazon and Microsoft are all building their Metaverse trying to capture as much of the &lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-web3/"&gt;"Web3"&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ I wrote an article about &lt;a href="https://jon.io/five-reasons-why-you-cannot-sell-your-nfts"&gt;why you cannot sell your NFTs&lt;/a&gt;. If you don't know how to make your NFTs, this is another article &lt;a href="https://jon.io/create-1000-nft-tickets-for-free-in-less-than-1-minute"&gt;how to do it for free&lt;/a&gt;. If you don't know what an NFT is, &lt;a href="https://jon.io/i-bought-this-image-for-1500-and-i-sold-it-for-50-in-two-weeks"&gt;here is a small intro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/MrD4oUk9LSWvj4oiYzWXKfFMGHaoWaNYfo5IebHH16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAOs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of the work, the future of companies and the heart of a Metaverse is a &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/cathyhackl/2021/06/01/what-are-daos-and-why-you-should-pay-attention/?sh=7b3a8bd7305f"&gt;DAO&lt;/a&gt;. A DAO is a bunch of algorithms that define the operations/rules of a company/team/country and people are responsible for the governance (by voting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a DAO can have 1000 members where all have chipped in to buy self-driving cars. These self-driving cars will be rented out, recharge on their own and the profits will go back to the DAO. A DAO can also hire people and pay them as a normal company. The difference is that all decisions are made by anonymous, fully remote citizens and are enforced by algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the &lt;a href="https://flamingodao.xyz/"&gt;FlamingoDAO&lt;/a&gt; buys and sells NFTs. 1hive hires people to build projects that make more money for the DAO. &lt;a href="https://www.olympusdao.finance/"&gt;OlympusDAO&lt;/a&gt; builds fully financial products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A DAO doesn't need an HR department. You pick up any task you want, you complete it, it gets reviewed and you get your money. There are a lot of people working on one or multiple DAOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ Ok, let's take a breather because this was A LOT of information. One thing I learnt as an Entrepreneur trying to sell products to big customers is &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/want-to-make-consumers-dissatisfied-with-a-product-tell-them-a-better-version-is-coming-11634752462"&gt;NEVER say that a new version&lt;/a&gt; or a new feature is coming out soon. You give them a "way out" to postpone their decision. You cannot come back from someone saying "oh, that's exciting! let's talk back when this feature is out".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ I recorded another &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/nUlE3gDqrvQ"&gt;Pitch Deck review&lt;/a&gt; and people are already interested in investing in this company. Check it out - a very good pitch deck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/GvX6Jiemel8mTnvsaOYxN6f3YuTVE8fZ9CIbaEpI16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/nUlE3gDqrvQ"&gt;Click here to see this epic video!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>The Squid game and the Art of not giving up</title><link href="http://jon.io/the-squid-game-and-the-art-of-not-giving-up" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-08T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-10-08:/the-squid-game-and-the-art-of-not-giving-up</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another crazy Friday (or Saturday depending on your time zone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I learnt so many new cool stuff that I don't think one email can do justice. But I'll try. Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ I am having a blast with my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdAC0o1hmy9JkYcph0GVrog"&gt;"Startup Office Hours" channel&lt;/a&gt;. This week …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another crazy Friday (or Saturday depending on your time zone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I learnt so many new cool stuff that I don't think one email can do justice. But I'll try. Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ I am having a blast with my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdAC0o1hmy9JkYcph0GVrog"&gt;"Startup Office Hours" channel&lt;/a&gt;. This week I reviewed another pitch deck (link here) and I believe my editing skills have improved tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I started doing these videos are to help as many Entrepreneurs as I can but also to learn a new skill: &lt;strong&gt;Visual Storytelling&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have any feedback (seriously &lt;em&gt;ANY&lt;/em&gt; feedback helps) on things that can be improved just reply to this email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/J7Eis1MdJok4slky2IC43Y9acwK9xq1KjiO82Zaj16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qvf5eaLzFys"&gt;Click here to see this epic video!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ I have been included in the &lt;strong&gt;100 Greek Innovators&lt;/strong&gt;. The article is in Greek but in short it says "Jon you are awesome".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/M50ODu7A5v6iHcq7iesdUCZBJOby93sKFwF6PFdY16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this was five years ago, I wouldn't stop talking about it. Currently the only person that tracks all these is my mother (and sometimes puts them into frames).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that I consider myself a "big deal" but these don't give me an endorphin hit anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of time I found what gives me that hit: &lt;strong&gt;building stuff&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day that I build something (could be a site, a video, even a post), I feel great. Strange feeling and I have no idea why this is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time ago &lt;a href="https://jon.io/maximize-what-you-love-minimize-what-you-hate"&gt;I wrote a post about it&lt;/a&gt; so maybe it can help you find your endorphin highs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ I cannot send an email and not include NFTs. Seriously, if you have no idea what NFTs, DAO and Blockchain mean, drop everything you do and start reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a post about NFTs and &lt;a href="https://jon.io/how-nfts-will-change-events-and-why-mark-cuban-is-a-genius"&gt;why Mark Cuban is a genius&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ The Squid game. There are going to be &lt;strong&gt;zero spoilers&lt;/strong&gt; so you are good if you haven't watched it yet (but do, it is awesome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/qgOfqtoFAQRismmq3qouvRrIUaDnMNpoC9eL7ZH216325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Squid game is the top show in 40 countries - and on its way to be Netflix's biggest show. It made an insane amount of money. But the script was &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/squid-game-script-was-rejected-for-10-years"&gt;rejected 10 years ago&lt;/a&gt; in its local market (Korea). What do we learn from this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commitment. If you believe on something, go for it. Life is not for playing it safe but for making a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big contributors of course are timing and location. This show might have been "too brutal" 10 years ago but now it is on "family airtime". And Netflix saw that the US will love a show like this and then the rest of the world will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ I am surprised that most people are still working 9-5 without at least knowing about the &lt;a href="https://nathanbarry.com/wealth-creation/"&gt;"ladder of wealth"&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/EMWwFmrh1KyOmyH07t54e7Xb7bVtUKfcffyGk2q816325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;a href="https://nathanbarry.com/wealth-creation/"&gt;excellent post&lt;/a&gt;, Barry talks about how you should progress from selling your time to selling products. This is a MUST READ even if you never plan to be an Entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: If you read this far, thank you! Reply and say what are you working on and how can I help you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>How I went viral on Instagram and why you shouldn't care</title><link href="http://jon.io/how-i-went-viral-on-instagram-and-why-you-shouldnt-care" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-04T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-10-04:/how-i-went-viral-on-instagram-and-why-you-shouldnt-care</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I keep on building more and more cool things, I am starting to respond even slower to my emails, text and messages. I am almost back to &lt;a href="https://jon.io/scheduling-meetings-like-arnold-schwarzenegger"&gt;scheduling meetings like Schwarzenegger&lt;/a&gt;. And that's a cool thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your inbox is not a todo list that everyone on the planet can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I keep on building more and more cool things, I am starting to respond even slower to my emails, text and messages. I am almost back to &lt;a href="https://jon.io/scheduling-meetings-like-arnold-schwarzenegger"&gt;scheduling meetings like Schwarzenegger&lt;/a&gt;. And that's a cool thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your inbox is not a todo list that everyone on the planet can add tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make an impact, &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; need to prioritize. Emphasis on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*you&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that sprinkle of wisdom (damn, that's a cool name for a song), here are the 5 epic things I learnt this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, reply to this email and tell me your epic thing you learnt this week and I'll include it in the next email. How cool is that! Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Another &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p3sfFOumJZo"&gt;Pitch Deck review&lt;/a&gt; is out and this time is about an eCommerce Startup. Excellent flow and solid progress. Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/X05amsQKelXqw20gsn9bjHvOKnd7oQwF6YJiAg0B16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p3sfFOumJZo"&gt;Click here to see this epic video!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ I think I figured out how to go viral on Instagram and it is annoying. Oh, it is very annoying. With a 7 second video, I got 42k likes (and still going up) and 400k views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how I did it (I plan to run a couple more experiments so &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/jonvictory/"&gt;follow me on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; if you want to be annoyed by the experiments):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) The most important thing is to include music in your post. Trending music. Instagram and Tik Tok prioritize posts with popular music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) No more photos. Videos. Short videos. Up to 10 - 15 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it. Experiment and play around. The &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CT-CLhKpLXM/"&gt;post is here&lt;/a&gt; if you want to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ I talked with a new Entrepreneur last week and she told me that she is terrified about how people will perceive her work. And by people I don't only mean customers but also friends and family. I told her what I tell to everyone in my &lt;a href="https://jon.io/pages/built-to-fail"&gt;free Startup course&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fail fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media amplified the success stories and all of a sudden everyone thinks that you can hit all the shots you take and if you don't, there is something wrong with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have something important to tell you and it is not that a lot of people fail. It is that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nobody. Cares.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The faster you realize this, the faster your life will improve and you can focus on things that &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ I keep getting so many questions about NFTs and whether are gambling or not. Here is an article about how an &lt;a href="https://www.thegamer.com/nft-evolved-apes-scam/"&gt;NFT creator run off with almost $3M&lt;/a&gt;. And it is not the only one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New technologies create new opportunities to make money fast and lose money faster. That doesn't mean that you should be blind. You should read as much as you can about this new exciting world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an article I wrote about &lt;a href="https://jon.io/i-bought-this-image-for-1500-and-i-sold-it-for-50-in-two-weeks"&gt;trading NFTs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ Now that &lt;a href="https://www.gq.com/story/seinfeld-netflix-episodes-cropped-widescreen-ratio"&gt;Seinfeld is on Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, it's a good time to watch this video on how &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=itWxXyCfW5s"&gt;Jerry Seinfeld writes a joke&lt;/a&gt; and the-now-famous &lt;a href="https://nickwignall.com/seinfeld-strategy/"&gt;method of kicking ass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy these newsletters and think a colleague, friend, or family member should read them, please get them to &lt;a href="https://jon.io/"&gt;sign up on this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I am making a post about things that people see while they are reading this email. Snap a photo right now (as long as it is not NSFW) and send it over!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>Drones flying inside your house, Twitter goes NFTs and BREATHE</title><link href="http://jon.io/drones-flying-inside-your-house-twitter-goes-nfts-and-breathe" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-01T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-10-01:/drones-flying-inside-your-house-twitter-goes-nfts-and-breathe</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is Friday (already!) and it is time for another email from your favorite Entrepreneur (that is me - I hope!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Last week I started reviewing Pitch decks that Startups are sending to me. I am already on the 3rd video and I think it is gets better and better …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is Friday (already!) and it is time for another email from your favorite Entrepreneur (that is me - I hope!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Last week I started reviewing Pitch decks that Startups are sending to me. I am already on the 3rd video and I think it is gets better and better. I would love it if you check it out and give me some feedback (and if you like &amp;amp; subscribe I'll give you a virtual high five!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X__PJmLnUAk"&gt;Check it out here&lt;/a&gt; (and find the hidden gems in the video ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="images/youtube/robo.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ Last year, &lt;a href="https://jon.io/how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country"&gt;I helped a whole country to fight COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;. It was crazy how much difference a single person can make. The biggest misconception is that we cannot make a change. I am here to tell you, that you - yes, YOU - can create and shape the world if you put your mind into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVA (the Machine Learning Platform that analyzed thousands of tourists), just made it into Nature. Yes, the biggest scientific magazine in the world. Which is crazy! Hopefully this work will inspire more people to build cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ I started training how I breathe - because how &lt;a href="https://jon.io/you-are-breathing-wrong"&gt;we are breathing is wrong&lt;/a&gt;. I plan to post some more articles about biohacking and how you can improve your performance and reduce your stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ &lt;a href="https://decrypt.co/82069/snoop-dogg-buys-xcopy-ethereum-nft-for-3-9-million"&gt;Snoop Dogg bought this image for $3.9M&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, the NFT space is still going strong. What, still not convinced? Twitter seems to be also adding NFTs to their platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/zZ65ikYpA0JWElypb10LTuem75N0MO9GX411EKoZ16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ Amazon released a &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/gadget-lab-podcast-523/"&gt;$999 robot&lt;/a&gt; that "runs" around your house. And a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"&gt;$250 drone&lt;/a&gt; that flies inside your house. And Facebook released a &lt;a href="https://www.sfgate.com/culture-columns/article/Facebook-Ray-Ban-sunglasses-Drew-Magary-16497129.php"&gt;pair of glasses&lt;/a&gt;. If you are wondering why, the answer is simple: Data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I love it when I interact with all of you. Press reply and tell me what are you working on. Maybe I can help.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry><entry><title>Startup Office Hours, NFTs and big acquisitions!</title><link href="http://jon.io/startup-office-hours-nfts-and-big-acquisitions" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-24T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T04:24:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-09-24:/startup-office-hours-nfts-and-big-acquisitions</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello hello hello! I am wondering what is the thing that you were doing right now and I interrupted you. I would love to know, so please reply to this email and let me know (and I'll tell you what the majority of our community is doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, right to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello hello hello! I am wondering what is the thing that you were doing right now and I interrupted you. I would love to know, so please reply to this email and let me know (and I'll tell you what the majority of our community is doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, right to the chase (in Greece we say "right to the cooked meat").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ I've started &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pn2w-ZYozDU"&gt;"Office Hours"&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube, where I review Startups &lt;strong&gt;for free&lt;/strong&gt;. So if you want to learn from others or you have an idea to review, check the detailed post right here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="images/youtube/fintechstartup.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ The first &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CT5fBcYPw9T/"&gt;NFT fashion line&lt;/a&gt; will go live pretty soon. If you have any idea about fashion (or lines :D), I would love to pick your brain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://sendfoxprod.b-cdn.net/media/MDjkUQ9XsQCnCTzoIHyxrsXS32skasumkMlxkdmG16325"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/ I read in one sitting Derek's new book &lt;a href="https://sive.rs/h"&gt;"How to Live"&lt;/a&gt;. Do yourself a favor and pick it up. It is a small but condensed book of knowledge and you'll keep re-reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/ &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/insider-weekly-mailchimp-uber-ron-klain-9-2021"&gt;Mailchimp got acquired for $12 Billion&lt;/a&gt; and the employees got Zero (with a capital Z). The founders walked away with $5 Billion each. Remember: getting a salary gets you through the day, getting equity gets you through a life (I don't even know if that makes sense, I just came up with it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/ SEC moves aggressively towards crypto by forcing Coinbase to drop their &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/following-sec-lawsuit-threat-coinbase-cancels-launch-of-lend-product/"&gt;lending product&lt;/a&gt;. The real question is whether the US (and subsequently the whole world) will embrace crypto or outlaw it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jon V (as in Victory)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Newsletters"></category></entry></feed>