<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jon.IO - productivity</title><link href="http://jon.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jon.io/feeds/productivity.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jon.io/</id><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><entry><title>Maximize what you love, minimize what you hate</title><link href="http://jon.io/maximize-what-you-love-minimize-what-you-hate" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-02-06T10:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-02-06:/maximize-what-you-love-minimize-what-you-hate</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is not a HELL YEAH, it is a HELL NO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 was a very strange year for all of us. A year where we had to reinvent ourselves and slow down. Slow down to think, slow down to reprioritize. Slow down to recharge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me it was a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is not a HELL YEAH, it is a HELL NO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 was a very strange year for all of us. A year where we had to reinvent ourselves and slow down. Slow down to think, slow down to reprioritize. Slow down to recharge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me it was a year I learnt a lot about me and what fuels me for a 10x performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt how to shoot my own videos (poorly), edit them (poorly-times-2), build better financial models for &lt;a href="https://agentrisk.com"&gt;AgentRisk&lt;/a&gt;, built products (that make money) faster and how to build a bigger audience that matters &lt;strong&gt;to me&lt;/strong&gt;. I even had a freaking 1 hour interview with &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WrES48wX6CQ"&gt;Ice-T&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad(?) thing is that I acquired some skills that I DEFINITELY didn't want. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I posted an article about how to &lt;a href="the-joy-journal"&gt;find the things that you love&lt;/a&gt;. This year I collected more metrics and I came closer to the things that make my day better. Maybe some of these findings can be applied to your life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lords of Summer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mood" src="/images/mood_of_the_month.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons that I moved to Los Angeles is because it is summer all year long. I love &lt;a href="addictive-design-using-unpredictable-rewards"&gt;the sport of the Gods&lt;/a&gt; but this summer I was also involved in a &lt;a href="how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country"&gt;huge humanitarian project&lt;/a&gt; where I architected and coded a whole system from scratch.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I freaking loved it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really missed writing code and building products that &lt;strong&gt;just work&lt;/strong&gt; instead of making sure I don't upset the SEC. Yes, having your own wealth management company and managing millions using algorithms might sound exciting but after a while it is soul crushing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that put me in an interesting situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the CEO of the best Wealth Management company in the planet is an amazing ego booster. It is a social status that is higher than "a guy writing code and building stuff".  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it seems that it just is "not fun" for me. I definitely plan to fix this this year by "making investing fun again". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surfing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly regulated areas that you cannot innovate fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping &lt;a href="https://agentrisk.com"&gt;only wealthy people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Weekend Warriors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mood" src="/images/mood_of_the_week.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mood this year was way better than last year (this is also attributed that I am a positive person in general and to my support network - I love you all btw) but there is a distinguishable uptick on Saturdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturdays are my "project" days. The days where I get to build small experiments to try ideas. Experiments that I have zero expectations that will ever get any traction but I've seen a couple of them getting a couple of thousand of followers. This blog is also one of these experiments by the way. It is also the days where I meet with friends and we barbecue in the backyard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fridays were my "meeting" days. I used to pack all my meetings on a Friday. Now I dedicate 3 hours *&lt;em&gt;per week&lt;/em&gt; in meetings that I won't learn something new or have an insane fun time. I plan to bring this down to 30 minutes per week by outsourcing everything to my (kickass) EA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No expectation experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending more time with friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If it is not a HELL YEAH, it is a HELL NO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mood" src="/images/mood.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I started focusing more on "life design" (I'll post more about &lt;strong&gt;life design&lt;/strong&gt; in the following weeks). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life design helps you build your day, week, month and year in a way that creates a perfect flow for you. It usually requires you to reprioritize your whole belief system but the main gist is if you are not ecstatic about something, you shouldn't do it. This new navigational framework is making ripples on the rest of my life as old milestones (like raising money for my company or even selling it) become swamps that will slow you down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core lies in finding the things that you are madly in love with and center your life around them while avoiding the things that you hate. Definitively not as easy as it sounds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It needs you to be true to yourself, crash your ego and reevaluate your whole day/week/month/year/life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is one of these things that starts as a whisper and ends up as a roar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone sends you an email for a meeting. You are "so and so" but because you are polite, you respond and have the 30m meeting that goes nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;definitely not&lt;/strong&gt; a HELL YEAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, I am not checking email (sometimes for a week) and then on new emails if it is not a &lt;strong&gt;hell yeah&lt;/strong&gt;, I might not even respond. I know, it sounds like an asshole move and I ALWAYS tried to respond to everyone in the past but this is not aligned with my current life design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard your time and &lt;a href="https://jon.io/3-tricks-to-smash-your-goals"&gt;control your calendar else someone else will control your life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I convinced you to spend at least 10 minutes and write down the things that you love and the things that you hate. It is the only step to become better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>The backfire effect: How to convince irrational people</title><link href="http://jon.io/the-backfire-effect-how-to-convince-irrational-people" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-15T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-10-15:/the-backfire-effect-how-to-convince-irrational-people</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is 10 am in the morning, no coffee, no time even for stretching, obviously no surfing and I am on the 4th call of the day talking to potential investors for my company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my life 4 years ago and I can tell you that none of these …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is 10 am in the morning, no coffee, no time even for stretching, obviously no surfing and I am on the 4th call of the day talking to potential investors for my company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my life 4 years ago and I can tell you that none of these calls went as I wanted to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 2 years later, $1M raised in a week - mostly uneventfulness. This is not some weird flex as everyone knows that fundraising is a soul-crashing experience, regardless how easy it may seem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;People are stupid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have ever discussed with someone about politics, art, music, sports, food, drinks, fashion, science or let’s say &lt;strong&gt;anything on any subject&lt;/strong&gt; then you agree with me (if not, &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; are stupid): &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are stupid because YOU are right and they cannot see how wrong THEY are &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, you cannot always scream "YOU ARE AN IDIOT" to their faces and go on with your day. Sometimes you need to convince them that your argument is solid and theirs it is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you are trying to raise money for your company and the investors cannot understand that your idea will be more earth shaking than the second coming of Jesus. Or that your political party is the only one that can save the country or why keto diet is the best diet in the world or why Bitcoin is a scam (it is a scam - please don’t argue with me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why people cannot stop being stupid and just agree with me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The backfire effect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are situations where the evidence are on your side. Literally like “the earth is not flat” kind of evidence, backed by science and backed by anyone else that has IQ over 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, there are people that THEY JUST DON’T get it. &lt;strong&gt;And what do you do?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You argue. You confront them with more and more and more evidence. More data. But they still act irrationally and cannot be convinced regardless the amount of evidence and data they are presented to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the called &lt;strong&gt;the backfire effect&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone is irrational, any evidence presented to them  is “fake” or irrelevant. Confronting them with more evidence &lt;strong&gt;cements&lt;/strong&gt; their belief because now you are treating them as if they actually have a valid argument and you are trying to debate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current Startup being a Wealth Management company, I have billions of stories to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When insanity knocks on your door&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I manage people’s money for a living. I’ve been also managing my money for a long time. That doesn’t mean that I am the best one out there (hint: I actually am) but I run circles around non-professional investors. Again, not because I am smarter but because I am using data and this is what I do full-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of people I met that have 100% wrong opinion about the market, about stocks, about what to buy and what to sell, &lt;strong&gt;is staggering&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is even more mind-blowing is that it is pretty easy to prove that I am right:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My investments make more money than their investments. It is super clear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again, they cannot be convinced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve met people that lost 30% of their money and they are still convinced that they did better (I am screaming silently, HOW?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The super interesting crazy fact is these exact same people will trust a con salesman and get ripped off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to convince the inconvincible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out that you cannot convince everyone. Some people might have their own personal reasons and they will never share them with you. It is exponentially more difficult with people that they &lt;strong&gt;think&lt;/strong&gt; they know better and &lt;strong&gt;think&lt;/strong&gt; that they are smarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid those people. They are toxic and a total waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest, there is one simple question. One question to start the “conversion” process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you find something that could be improved or that makes you unhappy with your current choice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This small crack of light will let you see their perspective and with &lt;strong&gt;empathy&lt;/strong&gt; you can understand why there is a push back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask a “flat-earther” what is &lt;strong&gt;one thing&lt;/strong&gt; that they disagree with the “flat earth theory”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask an investor if they could turn back time, what they would have made different. Any investments that might have be avoided? Any lost opportunities?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use empathy to relate and approach their point of view and I GUARANTEE you that even the most difficult and rigid people will crack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if they are idiots, doesn’t mean that you should be too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Oscar Sutton on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>I tried a Digital Sabbath and it was epic</title><link href="http://jon.io/i-tried-a-digital-sabbath-and-it-was-epic" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-11T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-07-11:/i-tried-a-digital-sabbath-and-it-was-epic</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nassim_Nicholas_Taleb"&gt;Nicholas Taleb&lt;/a&gt; once said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three most harmful addictions are heroin, carbohydrates, and a monthly salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If he was an Entrepreneur living in Los Angeles or San Francisco he would know that the quote should be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three most harmful addictions are carbs, a monthly salary and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nassim_Nicholas_Taleb"&gt;Nicholas Taleb&lt;/a&gt; once said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three most harmful addictions are heroin, carbohydrates, and a monthly salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If he was an Entrepreneur living in Los Angeles or San Francisco he would know that the quote should be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three most harmful addictions are carbs, a monthly salary and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend too much time online. Way too much time. Based on Space (&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mrigapps.andriod.breakfree.deux&amp;amp;hl=en_US"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/space-break-phone-addiction/id916126783?mt=8"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;, sometimes &lt;strong&gt;I spend more than 7 hours per day&lt;/strong&gt; just on my phone. Yes, sounds a lot and you will be surprised how much time you actually spend without even realizing. Google Maps, Spotify, Gmail, Phone calls, calendar, 
etc etc really adds up. See, I didn’t even add Facebook, Reddit, Twitter, Instagram or Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tell you the truth, as an Entrepreneur I don’t need an office but that means that I work a lot on the go (thus the glued phone on my hand). Nah, this is just an excuse! STOP FOOLING YOURSELF!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time for a change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday morning I decided to try a Digital Sabbath. What is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Sabbath is a hipster way to stop using digital devices for a whole day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My rules were simple: No phones, no tablets, no laptops and gaming devices. And definitely no Internet. Sounds easy right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My morning started having breakfast in the backyard without having Netflix or YouTube in the background. And of course no music (no Spotify). Damn, I should have gotten an old fashion radio. Maybe order it from Amazon? Damn, no Amazon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I finished building a gym in my house that I’ve been postponing for some time but hey, Instagram stories during the weekends are so juicy (update: no, they are not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could hear my phone ringing (I should have turned it off but now I am not allowed to touch it) and probably it’s my friends trying to coordinate for coffee, drinks, activities. I hope someone drops by so I can tell them about my sabbath. And I really want to be blasting Black Sabbath when they arrive but I don’t know any Sabbath songs on the guitar except Paranoid and I cannot go online to find tablatures. Yes, this is &lt;a href="https://people.com/politics/trump-boasted-of-avoiding-stds-while-dating-vaginas-are-landmines-it-was-my-personal-vietnam/"&gt;my personal Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward, one of my friends dropped by for coffee and propagates the news to our network. I could hear the laughs behind every blink-blink of the Facebook Messenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now it is time for coffee! And has to be somewhere near by as we have a No Google Maps policy. Or at least I cannot use Google Maps. As I wonder if we should go outdoors or indoors I almost caught myself asking “Hey Google, what’s the weather today?”. Not today Google. Not today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrive at the coffee place while chatting in the car without anyone checking Twitter, Facebook or Instagram as I have this profound energy consuming the social space around me and I say “coffee is on me”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Digital Sabbath made me realize how awesome technology is and how ingrained is in our everyday lives. And &lt;strong&gt;apparently you cannot even buy coffee at coffee shops without using a tablet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day turns into night and we go out for drinks and then food and I end the day reading a &lt;strong&gt;physical book&lt;/strong&gt; which I had mostly as decoration as I do all my reading on Kindle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved every single bit (ha! puns!) of the experience. I really enjoyed waiting in line and not checking my phone and just watching people (checking their phones). It was a strange meditative exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It actually seemed that people became more talkative and open. Who knew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Am I doing it again next Saturday?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OF COURSE! But I will optimize it a little bit. This impromptu digital seclusion made communicating with friends &lt;em&gt;adventurous&lt;/em&gt; (at least in the beginning) as no-one knew about my experiment. Now they will know that we just have to stick to plans we made from Friday and they have to help me get coffee. Oh and I will definitely buy a small radio (in your face Spotify).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>3 tricks to smash your goals</title><link href="http://jon.io/3-tricks-to-smash-your-goals" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-13T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-06-13:/3-tricks-to-smash-your-goals</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do you feel unmotivated? Lethargic? Overwhelmed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you are like &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt; else!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all find reasons not to do stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find reasons not to exercise (I don’t have time - I feel tired).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find reasons not to eat healthy, find time for ourselves or maybe read that book …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do you feel unmotivated? Lethargic? Overwhelmed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you are like &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt; else!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all find reasons not to do stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find reasons not to exercise (I don’t have time - I feel tired).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find reasons not to eat healthy, find time for ourselves or maybe read that book that I bought from Amazon about bird watching and I am waiting for the weather to be perfect so I can sit in my backyard to identify the birds but it is a bit cold and I don’t know whether birds fly that much when it is cold, maybe next weekend or…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough with the chit-chat. Let’s do some smashing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 3 tricks to smash your goals RIGHT NOW&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control your calendar. Else time will control you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control your energy levels. Else you are fighting yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control who surrounds you. To flourish you need nutrients and not &lt;a href="it-is-bullshit-that-you-are-the-average-of-the-5-people-you-spend-most-time-with.html"&gt;toxicity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 (bonus)/ Relinquish control. Practice no attachment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1/ Controlling your calendar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to have tons of meetings back to back. I implemented &lt;a href="scheduling-meetings-like-arnold-schwarzenegger.html"&gt;this trick from Arnold&lt;/a&gt; and it worked but I found a state of mind that was more efficient:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever someone asks for a meeting, I treat it as if they are stealing from my personal time. They are stealing from the time I have to help people, be with the ones I love or work on my company and my goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes me very conscious about random meetings and I dedicate more energy for the meetings that matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a non-essential meetings is scheduled right now or after 2-3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2/ Control your energy levels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is literally a game changer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love answering emails and writing articles in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like reading at 11am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be done with exercising before 2pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like having calls after 2pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to fit everything based “on time of the day” instead of your personal energy levels is 100% wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to listen to yourself and figure out the times you are more creative, have more energy or you need downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to do it is track when you kick ass in your &lt;a href="/the-joy-journal.html"&gt;Joy Journal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3/ Control who surrounds you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard that “you are the average Of The Five People You Spend The Most Time With”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are toxic and bad-mouthing others behind their back, that negativity will cloud your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are bitching all day long about how others are responsible for everything, you will never get charge of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="it-is-bullshit-that-you-are-the-average-of-the-5-people-you-spend-most-time-with.html"&gt;You will become the people that surround you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 (bonus)/ Relinquish control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in Japan, I attended a seminar about Mandala. The idea behind it is that you spent A LOT OF TIME to create something beautiful and then you have to destroy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, it seems like the definition of wasting time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this exercise taught me that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is forever&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting go is part of evolving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denounce control to regain control&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave you today with a video I got when I was riding the Bullet Train in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qgLTHzV47tg" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have any tricks that help you become a “better” you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to hear them - just send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>Fund YOU: How to make fundraising 1000x times easier</title><link href="http://jon.io/fund-you-how-to-make-fundraising-1000x-times-easier" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-13T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-06-13:/fund-you-how-to-make-fundraising-1000x-times-easier</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are an Entrepreneur and have a pulse, fund raising is one of the worst things that you have to deal when you are running a Startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I am going to show you &lt;strong&gt;how to love it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negotiating is the most important skill that any Entrepreneur should have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are an Entrepreneur and have a pulse, fund raising is one of the worst things that you have to deal when you are running a Startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I am going to show you &lt;strong&gt;how to love it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negotiating is the most important skill that any Entrepreneur should have. And it is the only skill that helped me save my company a couple of times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked before about &lt;a href="win-in-every-negotiation.html"&gt;information asymmetry&lt;/a&gt; which is a fancy word for knowing something that the other person doesn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last two times I raised money for my Startup, I did it through &lt;a href="https://fundersclub.com/learn/safe-primer/safe-primer/safe/"&gt;SAFE&lt;/a&gt;. It also took me just a week to close the round but that is another story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAFE has many advantages (and disadvantages of course) but the most important advantage is that it gives you &lt;strong&gt;an informational edge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NUMBER ONE issue that I face whenever I am fund raising is having the first couple of investors &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt;. After that it is much easier. So much easier. But what usually happens is that everyone waits for the other person to make the first move and then &lt;strong&gt;ALL of them have to go together at the same time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/bulls.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or even worse, you round has to close at a specific date and if you don't have all your investors lined up - poof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You.should.never.do.this&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAFE gives you the informational edge as your investors can come in random order. You can even have your round open all year long if you want. There is no start and end date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your fund raising conversation should be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey we have a round open, with minimum $25k to fund our sales. The cap is $10M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes it more interesting is that you can give different terms to different investors (we call this &lt;strong&gt;high resolution investing&lt;/strong&gt;) based on how early they join the round, their importance or the amount money the put in your company. All with the same, super simple document. Pure epicness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For early investors, I am willing to give a cap of $3M and 10% discount. After I reach $500k, I won’t give any discount but one investor that I consider strategic I want her to join so I give her a cap of $2.5M and 10% discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 6 months, I am killing it but I have a couple of people that are still interested so then can join with a $5M cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same document. No legal fees. Plus, you don’t corner yourself by having to coordinate with all the investor and push them to commit before an end date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever tried doing fund raising using Converting Debt or equity, first of all you are an idiot and second of all open your eyes and see how it is done with SAFE. Unless you are a masochist. Or an idiot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>It is bullshit that you are the average of the 5 people you spend most time with</title><link href="http://jon.io/it-is-bullshit-that-you-are-the-average-of-the-5-people-you-spend-most-time-with" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-06T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-06-06:/it-is-bullshit-that-you-are-the-average-of-the-5-people-you-spend-most-time-with</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am pretty sure you’ve heard the saying that you are the average of the 5 people surrounding you, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have something to tell you that it is terrifying: It is bullshit because it is worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You will become the people that surround you.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your group is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am pretty sure you’ve heard the saying that you are the average of the 5 people surrounding you, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have something to tell you that it is terrifying: It is bullshit because it is worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You will become the people that surround you.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your group is toxic and bad-mouthing others behind their back, you will start too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are bitching all day long about how others are responsible for everything, you will start too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they love their 9-5 job and you want to be an Entrepreneur, I have some bad news for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Action plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drop anyone that is bad mouthing others&lt;/strong&gt;. And I am not talking about teasing. You need to focus your time and energy on building cool stuff and not talking about other people’s lives. Everyone has their own issues and problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop bitching (unless it’s for releasing stress)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add diversity&lt;/strong&gt;. For me that was a huge pivotal point in my life. I am blessed that I have friends with different backgrounds, different opinions and different goals in life. Thank you :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put something recurring on the calendar&lt;/strong&gt;. I love having our Thursday basketball or our “guys night out” (where we don’t go out but we have barbecue). Creating traditions with friends is what creates stronger connections. Plus, if you cannot stand a person over a barbecue, well… you know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>The beauty in being the underdog</title><link href="http://jon.io/the-beauty-in-being-the-underdog" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-29T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-03-29:/the-beauty-in-being-the-underdog</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the last three months, I am (kind of) doing a show by Entrepreneurs for Entrepreneurs. I know, I know you are going to tell me that “everyone is doing a podcast or has a YouTube channel nowadays”. And I agree. But hear me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of podcasts …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the last three months, I am (kind of) doing a show by Entrepreneurs for Entrepreneurs. I know, I know you are going to tell me that “everyone is doing a podcast or has a YouTube channel nowadays”. And I agree. But hear me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of podcasts out there and more YouTube channels about Startups and hustling that I won’t even bother looking for a link to back this up with some data. Trust me on this one. But 99% of those, talk to the same people about the same freaking thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, you graduated from Stanford, had an idea, raised money and then the company got acquired? How awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about the underdogs? The people that for one reason or another cannot go through that path?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Long live the underdogs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love being the underdog, the outsider. The person that has the least chances of succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends told me that I thrive in that state because it removes the anxiety of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you fail, it is expected. And if you succeed, you are 🚀.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that being the underdog forces you in a continuous state of competition. You take nothing for granted and you need to keep fighting. Hustling. You have to keep finding ways to come on top so you innovate. You pivot. You take more chances and you cannot stop because you are not Number 1. Hell, you are not even in the first ten places!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know what, sometimes everything just works. You get in that flow and things are starting to click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The underdog mentality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, getting to that state is pretty easy. I just start something new that probably will fail majestically (like a book, a podcast or planning to become the Major of Los Angeles) that I have no idea how to do and I try to do it. Succeeding doesn’t matter (in the beginning) because I get to learn SO many cool skills and I get to get over my “everything has to be perfect” plague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people love to watch Netflix or read a book. I just like to fail :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or as Ice-T said in one of my episodes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are good at something, you learn how to get good at something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>Jack of many trades, Master of Anything</title><link href="http://jon.io/jack-of-many-trades-master-of-anything" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-09T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-03-09:/jack-of-many-trades-master-of-anything</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; being focused is awesome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest resolutions for 2020 was to guard my time and energy like Cerberus - the multi-headed dog who guarded the gates of the Underworld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason is that I need more time for my projects. Besides &lt;a href="https://agentrisk.com"&gt;AgentRisk&lt;/a&gt; that takes most of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; being focused is awesome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest resolutions for 2020 was to guard my time and energy like Cerberus - the multi-headed dog who guarded the gates of the Underworld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason is that I need more time for my projects. Besides &lt;a href="https://agentrisk.com"&gt;AgentRisk&lt;/a&gt; that takes most of my time, I have tons of other projects that compete for my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of them are small - like releasing &lt;a href="why-i-wrote-a-book-about-my-hands.html"&gt;my book&lt;/a&gt; in a printed version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other projects are on-going - like using &lt;strong&gt;petri dish for my biohacking experiments&lt;/strong&gt; or learning Russian. And others are much bigger - like the soon-to-be-released TV Show or improving my drawing skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short, I could do 16 hours non-stop every day for 6 months and I wouldn’t be done with half of my projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the goal is not to be done. I enjoy the process. I literally enjoy having many hobbies and learning new stuff. &lt;strong&gt;And it only makes me better at everything&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jack of all trades, master of none&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The saying “Jack of all trades, master of none” is criminally stupid. It wasn’t even applicable when the whole of humanity was working on the fields and we had to specialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know how to seed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t need to learn about business. I don’t need to learn about the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t need to know about trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t need to know about economics. No need to know about computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ticket straight to unemployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reroute to remain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take your “idol” and see how he/she knows more than their craft. &lt;strong&gt;Way&lt;/strong&gt; more. Usually, they merge ideas from different fields and create something new. &lt;strong&gt;Jack of many trades, Master of Anything&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any intelligent creator understands that you need to control the whole creative process and that means that you have to know way more than your main craft. The most successful musicians not only have their own record company but they have expanded to other fields totally unrelated to their profession. And they kick ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my friend Ice-T said in one of my episodes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are good at something, you learn how to get good at something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you acquire a new skill &lt;strong&gt;at any level&lt;/strong&gt;, your chances of success are multiplying x2. Or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand why people get intimidated when they hear about new projects. Usually, they struggle with just their everyday job and they cannot understand that to grow they need to be cross-pollinated by different skills in different fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, being focused is &lt;strong&gt;an amazing thing&lt;/strong&gt; if you are a drone, want a 9-to-5 job and have zero creativity. But we are already suppressed enough in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let your inner creator make a mess. That’s the only way we grow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>The Joy Journal</title><link href="http://jon.io/the-joy-journal" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-08T10:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-02-08:/the-joy-journal</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;💻I am a data geek and I’ve been collecting data about me for the last eight years. Data like weight, fat percentage, Resting Heart Rate, Blood Pressure, Glucose levels and recently HRV, SP02, V0Max and a dozen more. Most of these data are tracked automatically by inexpensive hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;💻I am a data geek and I’ve been collecting data about me for the last eight years. Data like weight, fat percentage, Resting Heart Rate, Blood Pressure, Glucose levels and recently HRV, SP02, V0Max and a dozen more. Most of these data are tracked automatically by inexpensive hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019 I started tracking my mood on a daily basis, hoping to find any corrections that might be interesting.
&lt;img alt="data is king" src="/images/hrvdata.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22.2% was epic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70% was pretty good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7% was ok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.8% was bad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0% was terrible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it was a pretty good year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is kind of difficult to explain and quantify “happy” as my definition of happiness is something between building stuff, lifting heavy weights (and getting physically injured), Startups (getting emotionally injured) and doing stuff with people I love. No pain, no gain, no happiness, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone asked me on LinkedIn why my 2019 was (in general) a pretty happy year. Was it gratitude? Friends? Drugs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I have no idea. I remember being super happy with Katya and friends, laughing, going on the beach and chilling in the sun. I remember being happy when we did a kick-ass release at AgentRisk and I was dropping off Alex 11pm at his home — knowing that the whole team gave their 110%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don’t remember the exact moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;📖Enter Joy Journal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this year I am trying a Joy Journal — with a twist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joy journal is a physical book where you right things that make you happy. Then, you keep doing these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, data geeks love actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My JJ (that’s how cool kids call Joy Journal — and by “cool kids” I mean only me at this moment) is like a normal journal but with more data. Whatever you have in your mind. Double it. And then double it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="data" src="/images/dataguy.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use my phone instead of a physical book and I write down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time &amp;amp; date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who else is with me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The environment (context)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why I feel happy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also snap a picture and put everything in my Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to find the things (and the environment) that make me consistently happy and keep having more of it. No idea if that simple method will work out but it worths the shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you tried a Joy Journal? Do you have any cool ideas? I would love to hear them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>Scheduling meetings like Arnold Schwarzenegger</title><link href="http://jon.io/scheduling-meetings-like-arnold-schwarzenegger" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-12T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T11:47:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2018-06-12:/scheduling-meetings-like-arnold-schwarzenegger</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What you are about to read, is one of these things that you are going to say “I couldn’t never do that because bla bla bla”. I have to stop you right there and tell you that you are wrong and I am right and I am awesome and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What you are about to read, is one of these things that you are going to say “I couldn’t never do that because bla bla bla”. I have to stop you right there and tell you that you are wrong and I am right and I am awesome and you should shut up and read this epic post that will change your life. Ready? Let’s do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Total Recall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading a new book that talks about Arnold’s life, called &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Total-Recall-Unbelievably-True-Story/dp/1451662440"&gt;Total Recall&lt;/a&gt; and he mentioned how he books appointments and generally manages his day and time. And when I say Arnold, I mean &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Terminator"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_career_of_Arnold_Schwarzenegger"&gt;Arnold&lt;/a&gt; in case you &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arnold_Schwarzenegger#Mr._Olympia"&gt;didn’t understand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His trick is pretty simple and he’s been doing it for more than 20 years. Here it goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnold Schwarzenegger doesn’t have a weekly or monthly schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that Arnold doesn’t schedule ANY &lt;strong&gt;appointments&lt;/strong&gt; in the future. Do you want to talk to him? You can do it later today and that’s it. Or if it is super important, you can talk to him &lt;strong&gt;right now&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That way Arnold can focus on what is &lt;strong&gt;important to him&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;focus&lt;/strong&gt;, instead of having his whole life dictated by Google Calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What? It is an image of Arnold and a Calendar. Point made." src="/images/fat.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we are getting to the part where you say to yourself: I cannot do that! I have people to meet, business meetings, skype calls etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The part where you say bullshit to yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Founder (currently on my fourth Startup) and an Angel Investor and my schedule for at least three weeks in advance is sold out. And I am not bragging because &lt;strong&gt;this sucked&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that if I (and the Governor of California) can do this, you can do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I decided to give it a try and not schedule meetings for more than 3 days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some interactions, it was flawless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, I want to ask you for a new crypto strategy, how is your schedule next week?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello there! I try not to schedule any meetings that far into the future in order to focus on what’s important right now. Do you have time to meet tomorrow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure! Let’s do it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Jon, we are still trying to figure out how this integration will work. Maybe setup a meeting at the end of the month?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Andy, I try not to schedule meetings that far into the future so let’s talk tomorrow or around the end of the month to set something up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, ok. Let me see if we can do something this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it didn’t work AT ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey man, we plan to have a Founder’s meeting in a couple of weeks from now. Are you coming (I need to confirm seating).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yo, I suppose but can we please talk next week again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s this bullshit TimFerris-y thing that you are doing, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Ferris is a fake Entrepreneur, I am doing the Schwarzenegger thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Will I keep doing it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 3 is almost over and again my life is dictated by Google Calendar but only 3 days in the future (faint hoooraaaay).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The huge difference is managing my energy levels&lt;/strong&gt; (which maybe is more important than managing time) because I can arrange meetings based on what I feel working on right now and focus on what is important for me and the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check back with me in a couple of weeks ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry></feed>