<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jon.IO - Projects</title><link href="http://jon.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jon.io/feeds/projects.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jon.io/</id><updated>2021-10-17T05:28:46-07:00</updated><entry><title>Startup Office hours</title><link href="http://jon.io/startup-office-hours" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-21T13:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T05:28:46-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-09-21:/startup-office-hours</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing that I love more than build stuff is helping out Entrepreneurs. &lt;a href="/pages/my-story"&gt;I was helped&lt;/a&gt; when I started so the least I can do is pay it forward. That has a &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; downside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day I get around 100 emails from Entrepreneurs asking for my feedback/help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing that I love more than build stuff is helping out Entrepreneurs. &lt;a href="/pages/my-story"&gt;I was helped&lt;/a&gt; when I started so the least I can do is pay it forward. That has a &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; downside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day I get around 100 emails from Entrepreneurs asking for my feedback/help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I love it, it goes against my two rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do undistracted deep work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact as many people as I can&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why I decided to streamline the process and start "The Startup Office Hours".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reviews in the open&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every week, I'll pick one Startup that has &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/ARhTF4DydhqGizuK6"&gt;submitted an entry&lt;/a&gt; and I'll do a video review of their pitch deck and/or website. For free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I'll have a chat with the team and sometimes I'll bring some subject matters experts, angels and VCs to provide some feedback.
That way, I can impact as many people as I can (instead of repeating the same stuff to every Startup) and for the founders, well, 
my network consists mostly of Angel Investors, VCs and Entrepreneurs that can help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here it is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pn2w-ZYozDU"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/youtube_episode_1.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go and check the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pn2w-ZYozDU"&gt;first video&lt;/a&gt; and subscribe to the YouTube channel. Oh, I am planning to post highlights on my Instagram account, so feel free to &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/jonvictory/"&gt;follow me there too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an Entrepreneur that wants a review, &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/ARhTF4DydhqGizuK6"&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please share this to anyone that might benefit from this and let's make this a valuable library for Startups.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>I organized my own conference like Gary Vee in 30 days</title><link href="http://jon.io/i-organized-my-own-conference-like-gary-vee-in-30-days" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-27T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T05:28:46-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-07-27:/i-organized-my-own-conference-like-gary-vee-in-30-days</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year (2021 for the visitors from the future), I run my first own conference: &lt;a href="https://jon.io/metaverse2021"&gt;"V as in Metaverse"&lt;/a&gt;.
It didn't have thousands of attendees (because there is a thing called &lt;a href="how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country"&gt;COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;) but it had &lt;a href="how-nfts-will-change-events-and-why-mark-cuban-is-a-genius"&gt;NFTs as tickets&lt;/a&gt;, tons of sponsors and happened in the best place you can be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year (2021 for the visitors from the future), I run my first own conference: &lt;a href="https://jon.io/metaverse2021"&gt;"V as in Metaverse"&lt;/a&gt;.
It didn't have thousands of attendees (because there is a thing called &lt;a href="how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country"&gt;COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;) but it had &lt;a href="how-nfts-will-change-events-and-why-mark-cuban-is-a-genius"&gt;NFTs as tickets&lt;/a&gt;, tons of sponsors and happened in the best place you can be for the summer - Greece. If you don't believe me ask &lt;a href="https://greekreporter.com/2021/07/04/jeff-bezos-vacation-greece/"&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://greekcitytimes.com/2021/06/28/justin-bieber-and-his-wife-hailey-getaway-to-greece-mykonos/"&gt;Justin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/metaverse_selfie.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the story how (and why) this conference started right &lt;a href="https://jon.io/organizing-a-crypto-conference-in-europe-in-less-than-a-month"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this as a guide on how to do your own conference or a huge meetup. And maybe bug &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/garyvee"&gt;Gary&lt;/a&gt; to use this brand new &lt;a href="create-1000-nft-tickets-for-free-in-less-than-1-minute"&gt;NFT-as-tickets&lt;/a&gt; technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free also to &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/s/aGlnaGxpZ2h0OjE3OTU5MDE1MTM4NDYwNjk2?story_media_id=2597301977270937775_35696786"&gt;check some highlights&lt;/a&gt; on my Instagram. Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Took me 1 month to organize it and execute it (while I was vacationing in Greece)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the same effect as in weddings. If you have one year, it will take you one year of planning. If you have 1 week, it will take you one week of planning. Not relevant but my wedding took me 1 week from planning to execution. Some people call this (the effect, not my wedding) the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law"&gt;Parkinson's Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, you either need to cut corners &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; have an epic team helping you out. I am blessed that I had an amazing community helping out, making intros to sponsors, even helping with coordination and finding us space. I love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/people.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take away: Don't over-thinking it and don't over-engineer it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use NFTs as tickets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built my own NFT ticketing system and used it, front-running Gary here (sorry Gary).
If you want to learn more about the technology and how to create your own NFT tickets (it is trivial and free!), check this post (&lt;a href="create-1000-nft-tickets-for-free-in-less-than-1-minute"&gt;create your own NFT tickets for free in less than 1 minute&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For "V as in MetaVerse" I wanted people to experience "The Metaverse" and it was important for me to have everyone buy NFTs and use a cryptowallet. If we used "normal" tickets it would be lame (Bitcoin 2021 in Miami - I am looking at you). So I did the thing I know really well: destroying my vacations by writing smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The videos from the conference (we had a professional team from LA flying to Athens to document everything - thank you &lt;a href="http://www.northandtouth.com/"&gt;N&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt;) are going to be available to people that attended the event and own the NFT. How awesome is that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/clicknft.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take away: Practice what you preach. A crypto conference without using crypto is hilariously lame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More than 3200 subscribers in 2 weeks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to build a community? Be yourself and have fun. 
I was posting content &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/jonvictory/"&gt;non-stop&lt;/a&gt; and I was even posting videos while I was on vacations about how the conference was progressing. Of course we had tons of media sponsors and TV/Radio channels that kept pushing on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/haha.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take away: Be helpful, add value and keep pushing. Don't bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;COVID-19 strict restrictions (everyone must be tested or provide tests)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the most challenging part. Checking tests, wearing masks and not being able to have more than 50 people in one space. We could have done the conference in an open space but screen glaring and no WiFi was a no-go. Other than that, once you were inside the space (and your &lt;a href="create-1000-nft-tickets-for-free-in-less-than-1-minute"&gt;NFT ticket was scanned and verified&lt;/a&gt;), you were safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/working.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take away: Minimize red-tape and restrictions and if necessary, add them in the beginning of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do more of fun stuff - less of boring stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podiums and slides are terrible. Please stop doing this. We copied the format from my podcast &lt;a href="https://www.wearesiliconbeach.com/"&gt;Silicon Beach&lt;/a&gt; and all the presentations were fireside chats (or as I like to call them "firechats"). &lt;strong&gt;EVERYONE&lt;/strong&gt; loved them and most of the audience stayed for 6 hours listening to the speakers. On a Saturday. In Greece. During the summer. Yes, it was &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to talk with world class speakers is more interesting, engaging and the audience enjoys it way more. Do more of fun stuff, less of boring stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/risa.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take away: Run &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; favorite conference. Feel free to do stuff differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I got epic speakers flying in from the biggest companies on the planet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People flew from LA, NY, Monaco, London just to participate in my conference. I am forever grateful to them because this was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/eva.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We gave 2500 euros (~$3000) to participants of the hackathon (yes, we even had a hackathon)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the teams never wrote a smart contract before. But they did their first transaction on the blockchain and figured out how authentication works, how off chain solutions might be faster but have issues, what are these "gas fees" etc. Some teams came by train (6 hours) from Thessaloniki and kicked ass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I.freaking.loved.it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/maria.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't overthink it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My motto &lt;a href="https://jon.io/pages/built-to-fail"&gt;built to fail&lt;/a&gt; has never failed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/palikari.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start small&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn't the first time I was organizing an event. I have organized hundreds of events in San Francisco, Europe even in Japan and I was even the organizer of a Google User Technology Group (GTUG) so I had a good idea of how to run an event. Of course going from organizing small meetups to organizing a conference under &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; own brand was a huge leap of faith but you'll never know unless you try :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/metaverse2021/mitsos.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Was it easy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh no. Not easy AT ALL. I was crazy stressed and during the conference I skipped eating because I was the host of the firechats. But we had so many speakers and not a lot of time and I had to squeeze everyone in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was very gratifying. Most people from the conference went for food afterwards and I had the clarify of fasting &lt;strong&gt;plus&lt;/strong&gt; being around friends and intelligent people in my favorite place in the world. Awesome feeling.
But the 29 days before that were not fun :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Things that didn't work out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had 14 more sponsors that wanted to participate (and they have already signed up for next years' conference!) but I didn't have time to on-board them, collect payments and get their images and websites. I know it sounds easy but I had tons of other things that HAD to happen and I couldn't outsource this. So, one thing I should do is make the process of onboarding automated or at least easier to be done by someone else than me. Definitely a "fail" moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swag. Our swag provider didn't deliver on time. So we had no swag for the conference. Buuuuuut I am going to send swag to everyone that got a ticket. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration. It should have been a 3-day conference. 7 hours firechats are brutal. In my defence, I never thought we'll have all these amazing speakers flying to the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food. Damn you COVID! We were not allowed to bring food to the conference so in my "built-to-fail" fashion, I started going to "private lunches" with each team separately. Money was not an issue (thank you again sponsors!) but having to eat 5 times in &lt;em&gt;Day One&lt;/em&gt; and 0 in &lt;em&gt;Day Two&lt;/em&gt; was not balanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you made it this far, thank you and I would love to hear what you think. Send me a message on &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/eNWGH9GSMX"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; (or an email) - I always respond to all emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: How difficult is to create a crypto island?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category><category term="popular"></category></entry><entry><title>Organizing a crypto conference in Europe in less than a month</title><link href="http://jon.io/organizing-a-crypto-conference-in-europe-in-less-than-a-month" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-01T22:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T05:28:46-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-06-01:/organizing-a-crypto-conference-in-europe-in-less-than-a-month</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every summer I go to Greece to enjoy the Greek islands and every summer I end up spending a considerable amount of vacation time meeting with the Greek Startup community or getting &lt;a href="how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country"&gt;involved in huge projects&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;And I freaking love it&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to formalize this by doing a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every summer I go to Greece to enjoy the Greek islands and every summer I end up spending a considerable amount of vacation time meeting with the Greek Startup community or getting &lt;a href="how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country"&gt;involved in huge projects&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;And I freaking love it&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to formalize this by doing a yearly &lt;em&gt;"Jon V"&lt;/em&gt; conference where I meet my favorite, super smart Entrepreneurs and do a deep dive into technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing how the US is a bit "ahead" in terms of technology and blockchain adoption, I decided to run a &lt;strong&gt;"V as in MetaVerse"&lt;/strong&gt; conference and talk about NFTs, smart contracts, DAOs and Startups from inception, to development to productization. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's talk now about the agenda. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My original plan was simple: Get a huge airbnb, invite some people that want to learn and let's have a hackathon. But I think we can do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"V as in MetaVerse"&lt;/strong&gt; will take place sometime in the beginning of July in Greece. Maybe Athens? Maybe Kalamata? Maybe somewhere else? It all depends on the location I can find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tickets for the event will be &lt;strong&gt;NFTs&lt;/strong&gt;. A limited edition of NFTs will be given for &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; to volunteers, speakers and people that don't have the financial means to attend. The rest of the tickets/NFTs will be available at various prices ($10-$50). The reason there is a price, is because I want to weed out people that are not committed in coming and learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event will be three days. Day one, is presentations and workshops about blockchain development, NFTs, branding, fund raising, Startups and anything else we can fit in a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day two, is the hackathon and some networking events. You have 24 hours to build a kick ass blockchain project based on a theme to be announced. The first three teams will get a price from our sponsors.
 
Day three, in the morning, we select the winners and that's a wrap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of course will be available online a couple of weeks after the event. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is that it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha, of course not! There is a surprise in all this. A &lt;strong&gt;hidden&lt;/strong&gt; project that hopefully will be approved by the Greek government as it requires their permission and takes 5 to 10 years to complete. Let's just say for now, that the space where the event with take place, will be a "Metaverse blackhole". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sounds awesome. How can I help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking for speakers, people to help, sponsors, media sponsors and in general cool people :) If you are one of them or you can suggest someone, join the &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/XvCttdjTAM"&gt;Discord Server&lt;/a&gt;. There is a room to coordinate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Super excited and super stressed but it is going to be awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: If you bought &lt;a href="my-birthday-cake-as-an-nft"&gt;one of my NFTs&lt;/a&gt;, talk to me on Discord because you get a free ticket :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: How difficult is to create a crypto island?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>My birthday cake as an NFT</title><link href="http://jon.io/my-birthday-cake-as-an-nft" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-09T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T05:28:46-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2021-04-09:/my-birthday-cake-as-an-nft</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just released the NFT "Piece of cake" for my birthday! And there are two editions. And both of them are epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 9960 NFTs of the &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com/jonv/piece-of-cake_v2s1Oc8vg1/"&gt;first edition&lt;/a&gt; that cost &lt;strong&gt;Ξ 0.01&lt;/strong&gt; each. They have this epic NFT, pixelated and animated by me, stored in the brand new …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just released the NFT "Piece of cake" for my birthday! And there are two editions. And both of them are epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 9960 NFTs of the &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com/jonv/piece-of-cake_v2s1Oc8vg1/"&gt;first edition&lt;/a&gt; that cost &lt;strong&gt;Ξ 0.01&lt;/strong&gt; each. They have this epic NFT, pixelated and animated by me, stored in the brand new Decentralized App (DApp) of OMGDrops and on IPFS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="First edition" src="/images/jonscake.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com/jonv/piece-of-cake_v2s1Oc8vg1/"&gt;second edition&lt;/a&gt; costs &lt;strong&gt;Ξ 0.1&lt;/strong&gt; (UPDATE: it is sold out!), there are only 40 copies and has &lt;strong&gt;unlockable content&lt;/strong&gt;. The content is a numbered acrylic art block that contains the NFT and I will ship it wherever you live. For free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you didn't understand, this NFT comes also with a physical product, send to your place for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Unlockable content" src="/images/gift.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This NFT release pushed me to work more on our brand new infrastructure at &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com"&gt;OMGDrops&lt;/a&gt;. Here are some more geeky details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Piece of cake" is running on the brand new Decentralized App (DApp) of OMGDrops and IPFS. It is 100% decentralized running on the Ethereum blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you buy the NFT, it is immediately available AT NO COST at OpenSea. You can trade it there and make some sweet ETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The limited Edition NFT has unlockable content that is uses your wallet signature to unlock it and off-the-chain authentication. I am planning to open source this part because I haven't found anywhere how to do this at scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is built on Python/Flask, TailwindCSS and Solidity 0.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OMGDrops is still a hybrid. Some of our creators are not on the website, others are but we linked them on OpenSea or Rarible and some of them are 100% on the blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OMGDrops will become a fully Decentralized Autonomous Organization (DAO) by the end of 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OMGDrops DApp can be integrated with other websites &lt;strong&gt;with just one line of code&lt;/strong&gt;, helping artists sell their NFTs directly from their websites. How epic is that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in beta testing, sending me an email and we'll get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More technical details coming at a later post, so sign up to stay in the loop or drop by my &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/gEnk5f4web"&gt;Discord channel&lt;/a&gt;. Oh and don't forget to &lt;a href="https://omgdrops.com/jonv/pieceofcake_limited/"&gt;buy the NFT&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: How to hit $1M in sales with NFTs&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>How I spent my summer, helping to save a whole country</title><link href="http://jon.io/how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-10T10:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T05:28:46-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-11-10:/how-i-spent-my-summer-helping-to-save-a-whole-country</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was three months ago when my friend Kimonas asked me if I can help him with a huge secret project that he had on his mind. It was kind of a cheap shot as “huge secret project” are my trigger words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He asked me if I can join him …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was three months ago when my friend Kimonas asked me if I can help him with a huge secret project that he had on his mind. It was kind of a cheap shot as “huge secret project” are my trigger words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He asked me if I can join him on a Zoom at 6am. I told him that I am not going to wake up that early even if the President of Greece was on that Zoom call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the Prime Minister and his team of scientists were on the call and I was there, 7am in Los Angeles, half awake, wearing my “A.I pays my bills” t-shirt. The “huge secret project” was not clickbait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to build something that has never been built before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know Greece, I assume it is because you hate good food, sunshine, breathtaking beaches, history, and you haven’t watched “My Big Greek Fat Wedding”. And this comes from someone that is 100% impartial on this (being Greek doesn’t mean I cannot be impartial, right?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo by Jonathan Gallegos on Unsplash" src="/images/greece-ml.jpeg"&gt;
Photo by Jonathan Gallegos on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greece has a population of 11 million and during non-COVID19 summers, the country hosts more than &lt;strong&gt;33 million tourists&lt;/strong&gt;. This is &lt;strong&gt;more than 3 times the population of the entire country&lt;/strong&gt;. They all come to Greece and spend most of their time on the (tiny) Greek Islands. Oh, and most of them come &lt;strong&gt;during the three (summer) months&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tourism also supports nearly a quarter of the country’s jobs and represents 20% of the nation’s GDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of COVID19, this is a double-edged sword for the country. On one hand, keeping its borders closed to tourists equals &lt;strong&gt;financial suicide&lt;/strong&gt; for Greece — a country that had just started to recover from a previous financial hardship. On the other hand, blindly accepting &lt;strong&gt;100K to 300K tourists PER DAY&lt;/strong&gt;, translates to “Death by COVID19”, by putting the locals at risk of infection. To the best of our knowledge, there is no country that has the capacity to conduct these many tests or this kind of infrastructure or solution to pull this off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Meet EVA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVA is a country-wide AI screening and testing program , thought to be the first of its kind in the world, which has been online since July 1st 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="EVA" src="/images/eva.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you are one of the lucky ones that can work remotely. What better place to work from than the seaside, munching on tasty Mediterranean food. Again, 100% impartial on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before your arrival in Greece, you must fill out an online “passenger locator form” (we call it PLF) providing basic information including which country they are coming from, gender, age, and other details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After submitting your information to the GDPR-compliant system (Europe is extremely careful regarding how personal data is stored and handled), a subset of anonymized data arrives to EVA. EVA takes into account how many other people will arrive at the same entry point, availability of tests, and your personal risk profile and responds with a “TEST” or “NO TEST”. All in realtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “test/no-test” information is sent back to you via email and encoded as a QR CODE that will be scanned upon your arrival in Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immigration officer will know at the time of scanning whether you should be sent for testing or you are free to continue your vacations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are sent for testing, your (anonymized) lab results will be fed back to EVA to improve the model and its accuracy — closing the self-learning loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By digitizing the details of a visitor’s trip, Greece can make informed decisions on who should be tested, how tests should be allocated, or whether any borders need to be closed due to increasing risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How good EVA is?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal opinion (using only public data) is that EVA is working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-04014-z"&gt;The paper that details EVA made it into Nature!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Greece has less than 20 new external infections from 100k visitors per day. The total infections are on average 150 to 200 mostly to internal spread of the virus which is extremely low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know any other country that managed to stay open for as long as Greece while having thousands of tourists per day and open bars and restaurants. Of course if Greece wants to keep infections low, will have to impose stricter controls to manage “internal infections”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVA might seem like a “Deus Ex Machina” but as Greeks say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot expect everything from the Gods — you also have to put some work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;TeamEVA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVA is the brain child of three very smart people. And me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamsa-bastani-4a346955/"&gt;Hamsa Bastani&lt;/a&gt;, assistant professor of operations, information and decisions from the Wharton School at the University of Pennsylvania&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kimon-drakopoulos-a5663341/"&gt;Kimon Drakopoulos&lt;/a&gt;, assistant professors of data science and operations at the Marshall School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishal-gupta-usc/"&gt;Vishal Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, assistant professors of data science and operations at the Marshall School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://jon.io/pages/my-story"&gt;And me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole team is committed in open-sourcing the important parts of EVA and of course a &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-04014-z"&gt;full publication&lt;/a&gt; will be coming up in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more information if you follow these links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://pressroom.usc.edu/reopen-greek-economy/"&gt;USC Marshall, Wharton Researchers Team with Entrepreneurs and Policy Makers to Help Reopen Greek Economy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ldi.upenn.edu/news/ldiwharton-usc-collaborative-plays-key-role-greeces-covid-19-response"&gt;LDI/Wharton-USC Collaborative Plays Key Role in Greece’s COVID-19 Response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.marshall.usc.edu/news/data-driven-reopening"&gt;A Data-Driven Reopening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: Building Machine Learning frameworks for mobile devices&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I wrote a book about my hands</title><link href="http://jon.io/why-i-wrote-a-book-about-my-hands" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-30T10:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T05:28:46-07:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2019-12-30:/why-i-wrote-a-book-about-my-hands</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was 2015 and my Startup had just &lt;a href="https://www.splunk.com/view/SP-CAAAJJC"&gt;got acquired&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://splunk.com"&gt;Splunk&lt;/a&gt;, a multi-billion dollar Company in the Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Athens/Greece at that point and for the first time, I didn’t have to think 24/7 about customers, bugs and scaling the company. That was …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was 2015 and my Startup had just &lt;a href="https://www.splunk.com/view/SP-CAAAJJC"&gt;got acquired&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://splunk.com"&gt;Splunk&lt;/a&gt;, a multi-billion dollar Company in the Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Athens/Greece at that point and for the first time, I didn’t have to think 24/7 about customers, bugs and scaling the company. That was someone’s else problem now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that free mental cycles, I decided to focus my energy to something new (at least for me): a book. Or as I’ve been saying since then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE BOOK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pitched &lt;a href="https://whatidowithmyhands.com/"&gt;What I do With My Hands&lt;/a&gt; to my friend, &lt;a href="http://www.asiomou.com/"&gt;Anastasia&lt;/a&gt; and she loved the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, I &lt;strong&gt;loved&lt;/strong&gt; the idea - she just played along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;These 10 little Celebrities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met at my Airbnb in Athens (oh yes, I was staying in Airbnb all over the world for the last three years - hashtag StartupLife) and we came up with these cool(?) things that you can do with your hands. Why? Seriously, I don’t know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="It was on my todo list for a long time" src="/images/handtrello.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, the book spent &lt;strong&gt;five years&lt;/strong&gt; in my Trello todo list, taunting at me, laughing at me and promising eternal glory and recognition. The main reason was me, over-engineering the whole process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to find the perfect layout, website, page, intro everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as we all know, being a perfectionist is how you get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ship the fricking book!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019 has been a shifting year for me. I reevaluated so many things in my life but more importantly I decided that taking yourself seriously is the worst thing it can happen to your personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go back to basics and start creating more. And then some more. And then add on that. And the first step was releasing that book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/ikve"&gt;Vivi&lt;/a&gt;, made sure that it renders correctly on even the oldest of Amazon Kindle and then fought with the Amazon’s layout creator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used a free template for the website, got the domain, hosted the website on Github Pages and here you go. Available on Amazon and (in the next couple of weeks) available as a coffee table book. You’ll be able to read it soon in all the hipster coffee places in San Francisco and Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So, now what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t intend to make money from the book - I keep running “free book” promotions on Amazon but I can do only five days every 90 days. If you want to read it and don’t want to spend $2 on Amazon, send me an email and I’ll send you a PDF version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out that whenever I do “soul projects” expecting returns or outside validation I hate the process and I end up getting bored. I know, it is kind of obvious but I keep forgetting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry></feed>