<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jon.IO - Startups</title><link href="http://jon.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jon.io/feeds/startups.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jon.io/</id><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><entry><title>The Best way to measure real KPIs? Don't add a link to your product</title><link href="http://jon.io/the-best-way-to-measure-real-kpis-dont-add-a-link-to-your-product" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-23T10:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-12-23:/the-best-way-to-measure-real-kpis-dont-add-a-link-to-your-product</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whenever I build a new product, I follow this advice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Make the simplest version of your product first. Learn and iterate fast."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am building a course for Founders and I am coding my own platform for it (it's a long story) and the simplest way to see if the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whenever I build a new product, I follow this advice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Make the simplest version of your product first. Learn and iterate fast."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am building a course for Founders and I am coding my own platform for it (it's a long story) and the simplest way to see if the content is interesting was to start a &lt;a href="https://jon.io/pages/built-to-fail"&gt;simple newsletter course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first couple of days, I got more than 100 founders going through the course but I wanted to see how many of them are really interested about the full course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the last email where I talked about the course, I &lt;strong&gt;DIDN'T ADD THE LINK&lt;/strong&gt; to the full course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/f1.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/f2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/f3.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/f7.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/f8.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 founders sent me an email like this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 people that are interested in the course &lt;strong&gt;that much&lt;/strong&gt; to send me an email (or ping me on social media).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many people will click to check out the website shouldn't matter when you are trying to validate a product. 
You should be interested in how many people really want to connect with you and ask more questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Force your users to really ask about your product
(by the way this trick is also part of the full course - but I won't include a link here ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>Your blind spots will bring you down</title><link href="http://jon.io/your-blind-spots-will-bring-you-down" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-03T10:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-12-03:/your-blind-spots-will-bring-you-down</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is 1943 and you are Head of the United States Eighth Air Force. Your mission is to destroy Germany's ability to wage war and free up the skies for the Allied Forces. The problem is that your Bombers are being zapped out of the sky like mosquitos drawn into …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is 1943 and you are Head of the United States Eighth Air Force. Your mission is to destroy Germany's ability to wage war and free up the skies for the Allied Forces. The problem is that your Bombers are being zapped out of the sky like mosquitos drawn into the fire in a summery night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German anti-aircraft fire and Luftwaffe  - the German Air Force - are making your life hard. You cannot afford losing more Bombers and more personnel else the war is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution to most problems is data. Data is also the culprit of most problems but that is a different post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the WWII, the United States after suffering terrible losses turn to Statistical Research Group (SRG) that had the best statisticians in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/plane.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bombers had to be reinforced with metal in order to cover any weak points. Sadly, you cannot cover the whole plane with additional metal as metal is heavy. The weakest points had to be identified and only these points had to be patched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data collection started with analyzing the location of the bullet holes that were found on the Bombers that made it back safely. The obvious idea was to patch the areas that had the highest concentration of bullet holes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More bullet holes around the wings? Patch that part. More bullet holes around the tail? Patch the tail. Data driven decisions at its best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Looking for the missing bullets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was one critical issue with that theory: The US collected data from the planes that made it back, the planes that survived and obviously weren't blown out of the sky. If anything, they should have been looking to patch &lt;strong&gt;the areas that had no bullet holes at all&lt;/strong&gt;. The planes that went down were never included in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham Wald from SRG suggested, the  bombers were going down because they were shot &lt;strong&gt;at&lt;/strong&gt; the engines - an area that had zero bullet holes on the returning planes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making assumptions based on a winning, surviving dataset is called &lt;strong&gt;Survivorship Bias&lt;/strong&gt; and it can be devastating for Entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Looking for missing opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to idolize the person that worked for 5 years in a bad idea but at the end made it and now is a multimillionaire. Or the Entrepreneur that left a well paying job and decided to build a new company and now he has more money than the budget of a small European city. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Entrepreneurs, we learn to listen to the data but what happens when our whole dataset is made up from "planes that survived"? What happens when only 1% of bombers make it back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixing the blind spots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have blind spots. Every single one of us. We become better by making these spots as small as we can. We do that by stepping back and looking at the big picture instead of getting closer and closer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From up close, even a dot seems like a huge black hole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in finding what "brings us down" is start looking for what might be missing. A good example is customer reviews. 
Relying &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; on customer reviews is a terrible idea to improve your business. I know a Startup that had brilliant reviews but was bleeding customers. The majority of these customers never cared to provide any feedback - they just hated the product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same happens when you ask  for opinions from your friends or family. Even if they are hard on you, it is no comparison with the feedback you will get from strangers that don't care about your feelings. I am not saying that "all feedback is good", you still have to filter it but at least collect as much as you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you like getting blown out of the sky.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>This Product doesn't exist: Building products super fast</title><link href="http://jon.io/this-product-doesnt-exist-building-products-super-fast" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-31T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-10-31:/this-product-doesnt-exist-building-products-super-fast</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year I was obsessed with Generative Art - that's art that is generated using only algorithms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the image below, I forced an algorithm to draw me (yes, that's me) having learnt only about triangles. If you want to see more impressive art you should check out &lt;a href="https://tylerxhobbs.com/"&gt;Tyler Hobbs&lt;/a&gt; and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year I was obsessed with Generative Art - that's art that is generated using only algorithms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the image below, I forced an algorithm to draw me (yes, that's me) having learnt only about triangles. If you want to see more impressive art you should check out &lt;a href="https://tylerxhobbs.com/"&gt;Tyler Hobbs&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/generative/"&gt;sub-Reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Generative Art" src="/images/genart.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do we perceive shapes and ideas when we are forced to limit ourselves? Can we extract the basics of a product by eliminating the unnecessary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This bicycle does not exist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to &lt;a href="https://thispersondoesnotexist.com/"&gt;ThisPersonDoesNotExist&lt;/a&gt; and you keep refreshing the page, you will see every time a photo of person that doesn't exist. That photo has been generated by a Machine Learning algorithm that mashes millions of photos together and comes up with a new face every time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine introduced me to &lt;a href="https://www.gianlucagimini.it/portfolio-item/velocipedia/?fbclid=IwAR3mtHozjRDKoawWPS6PcYeltg4jvZucLnvuj4RrGkWWeRlVr0fhk5cvZv8"&gt;Velocipedia&lt;/a&gt;, a project where people are asked to draw bicycles from memory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bicycle" src="/images/artbike.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of the bicycles drawn have some vital flows. &lt;strong&gt;These bicycles cannot exist&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Gianluca Gimini says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little I knew this is actually a test that psychologists use to demonstrate how our brain sometimes tricks us into thinking we know something even though we don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about we do this for building products?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This Product Does Not Exist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last couple of months I am building a new platform that teaches you how to build a Startup &lt;strong&gt;fast&lt;/strong&gt; and the number one problem is overthinking about your first version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course the majority of founders are building their prototype without ever talking to at least 10 customers. Crazy right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am (obviously) guilty of overthinking too when it comes to product development so I decided to ask 20 users to draw, using only pen and paper, the landing page and one functional page. This could work with just 5 users by the way. This is the message that I've sent them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sent by me" src="/images/sentbyme.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try it yourself if you want before seeing the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I've learnt from the landing pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1/ What &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; like is not what my users like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img alt="Landing" src="/images/proone.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;90% of the landing pages had a video/teaser which is something &lt;strong&gt;my design didn't have&lt;/strong&gt;. I don't like having videos in landing pages but it seems that for educational content, it is a must.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Landing" src="/images/protwo.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2/ Users expect discounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Landing" src="/images/prothree.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the designs had a "free week" or "buy now and get X% discount". &lt;strong&gt;I have this too&lt;/strong&gt; (you get most of the chapters for free) but not in that prominent space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3/ Testimonials were not such a big theme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Landing" src="/images/profour.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every landing page that had testimonials didn't dedicate a lot of space to them and it was usually on the second page (under the fold). &lt;strong&gt;That was my wrong assumption&lt;/strong&gt;, thinking that I needed to have a good amount of testimonials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4/ Pay attention to interesting ideas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Landing" src="/images/profive.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some landing pages that were 100% different from the rest. I am definitely going to integrate some ideas from them. It what makes products different, interesting and fun to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I've learnt from the functional pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5/ Video is king - but text is his Queen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes, action lists, descriptions and extra resources. &lt;strong&gt;I HAD NO IDEA&lt;/strong&gt;.
 
Now it makes sense. Users want more material and want to be able to go back and look at their notes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Landing" src="/images/prosix.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6/ Group chat and discussions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Landing" src="/images/proseven.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a much more difficult feature but it seemed important for a lot of users. I would try using Slack/Discord before building something into the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Perfect User Does Not Exist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have built the landing user-generated landing page waaaaaay faster than the one I designed. Making assumptions and believing in them is the worst way to build a Startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn how your users can use your product, eliminate all your biases. Give them a pen and paper and tell them to draw the UI. Focus on the commonality, build fast and have them try it out again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, you cannot make everyone happy. The Perfect User Does Not Exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A huge thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goes to everyone who sent me their drawings! You get free access to the course &lt;strong&gt;forever&lt;/strong&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about the course, don't forget to sign up to the &lt;a href="/pages/weekly-tips"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go and make some products that don't exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: Selling a course to change the world&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>Addictive design - using unpredictable rewards</title><link href="http://jon.io/addictive-design-using-unpredictable-rewards" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-04T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-10-04:/addictive-design-using-unpredictable-rewards</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever high-fived the universe? If not, let me introduce you to &lt;strong&gt;surfing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is everyone surfing right now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blame it to the lockdown or to a ton of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_K3SMg088j8"&gt;YouTubers&lt;/a&gt;, surfing seems to have attracted a lot of people the last 6 months. Or maybe because &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; started surfing …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever high-fived the universe? If not, let me introduce you to &lt;strong&gt;surfing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is everyone surfing right now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blame it to the lockdown or to a ton of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_K3SMg088j8"&gt;YouTubers&lt;/a&gt;, surfing seems to have attracted a lot of people the last 6 months. Or maybe because &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; started surfing like a maniac. This is called by the way the &lt;strong&gt;Baader-Meinhof Phenomenon&lt;/strong&gt; or frequency bias. It is the same as buying a car and then you keep noticing that there are so many people driving the same car are you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried surfing as soon as I moved to Los Angeles from San Francisco. And I sucked. I mean, I enjoyed it and was spending more than two hours fighting with the waves and making little progress but swimming + exercising + friends is a pretty sweet deal. Then, I stopped. Until 6 months ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hooked&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I unlocked the next stage of surfing randomly, when I went to a beginners surfing point just to get some exercise, having &lt;strong&gt;zero&lt;/strong&gt; expectations about riding a wave. Oh, little did I know. All of a sudden I could ride waves. &lt;strong&gt;I COULD SURF&lt;/strong&gt;. It seems that trying to start surfing in a 3-4 feet waves which trust me &lt;em&gt;are huge&lt;/em&gt; when you are confronted by them, isn't the best intro for surfing. It builds your skills though: balance, explosiveness, paddling in the water and knowing how to dodge waves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was it. I was hooked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The sport of the Gods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winds are traveling the universe and end up on Earth caressing the ocean to create waves, harnessing the gravity of the moon and the sun and then this powerful and majestic mass of awesomeness is calling you to try and ride it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing similar to this feeling in the whole universe. You cannot be more connected with everything. You cannot feel smaller yet bigger than this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is not why surfing is so addictive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dogs, cats and rats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pavlof find out that &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any behavior that is rewarded, is likely to be repeated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He figured out that when a bell rings and you immediately reward a dog with treats, the dog will be condition to expect a treat (and salivate) whenever a bell is rung. We all know how this works and applied to products but Skinner took it waaaaay further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. F. Skinner was the father of behavior analysis. If you don't know about Skinner, please read this excellent book. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skinner figure out that he can boost the "salivating" (even though he was using mostly rats) by randomizing the reward. 
The rats were hitting a lever and they were getting a reward but not everytime. Sometimes the reward was small. Sometimes huge. Sometimes there was no rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rats were going crazy waiting for their random dopamine hit. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement#Schedules_of_reinforcement"&gt;This variable schedule of rewards&lt;/a&gt; is more effective that what Pavlof found out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why surfing is so addictive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adrenaline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are sitting on your board, waiting for the next "perfect" wave. Tons of waves come but none is perfect. Sometimes you spend 30 minutes just waiting. And then the universe sends you a wave. Randomly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see it and immediately you have an adrenaline rush. Dopanine is already hitting you, even before catching the wave. &lt;strong&gt;This is it&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You start paddling, you feel the gentle push that is becoming violent and as you are connected with everything, time stops. Nothing else matters. &lt;strong&gt;This is it&lt;/strong&gt;. Your reward that you got sometimes was epic, medium or a face-plant to the water. Regardless of the reward though, you are hooked. You want to do it again. You crave for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unpredictable rewards in products&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrating this to a product is not as tricky as you think and it is used in almost everything already (gaming, social networks, casinos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main idea is making any reward that you have for the user &lt;strong&gt;variable&lt;/strong&gt;. Not in terms of time but in terms of benefit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For gaming, any rewards should be randomized. You completed you quest? Fantastic! Here is your random &lt;strong&gt;loot box&lt;/strong&gt;.
For a platform that uses badges (which surprisingly are very effective), a &lt;strong&gt;random badge should be awarded&lt;/strong&gt; instead of a specific one. So many platforms are doing this wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anything that "unlocks" a next level - even buying a bigger plan, a random reward should be given. Users need to crave for the next cool thing that &lt;strong&gt;might get&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am experimenting with a Startup Course that I am building from scratch (everything, &lt;strong&gt;including the platform&lt;/strong&gt;) and I am seeing that random "powerups" have more than 60% engagement than predictable ones. Btw, if you want to participate in the beta of the Startup Course (The Donut Startup), &lt;a href="pages/weekly-tips"&gt;sign up here&lt;/a&gt;, send me an email and I'll send you an invite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever experienced unpredictable rewards that worked on you? I'd love to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming next: How to create an army of followers that love your product&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I've built a custom blog with Pelican and Tailwind</title><link href="http://jon.io/why-ive-built-a-custom-blog-with-pelican-and-tailwind" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-04T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-10-04:/why-ive-built-a-custom-blog-with-pelican-and-tailwind</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are so many website generators out there that let you build your website and blog in minutes. Why on earth someone will be building its own using &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; and not &lt;strong&gt;AT LEAST&lt;/strong&gt; NextJS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never had a personal website but I always had a blog. First on tumblr …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are so many website generators out there that let you build your website and blog in minutes. Why on earth someone will be building its own using &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; and not &lt;strong&gt;AT LEAST&lt;/strong&gt; NextJS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never had a personal website but I always had a blog. First on tumblr, then Jon.IO using Mailchimp, then on Medium and then on Substack. I loved them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought that &lt;a href="https://substack.com/"&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt; will be &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; blog/mailing list I will be using for a very long time (because substack is epic) but I wanted a little bit more control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Control = Conversions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, everything has to be calculated. How many users came to the website, from where, which pages are performing, which articles are shared the most etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Having my own website got me more than 2000 subscribers in two weeks with 5 articles &lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was a fluke. But I've been doing this for some time now and I know how to talk with my audience and what my audience likes (hint: mostly Startups, trading and bad puns).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, I am building a Startup Course on my own platform (because I want to include some features than are fun and aren't available anywhere else) and I want everything to be under the same theme and under my control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sure, sure. Why not NextJS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://substack.com/"&gt;NextJs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://tailwindui.com/"&gt;Tailwind&lt;/a&gt; let's you build website super fast. Like, come on. It is ridiculous how epic this combination is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that I don't like is using bleeding edge software for "boring things" like the infrastructure of my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican is extremely easy to hack around, it will be working as it is for the next decade and if not, I can rebuild it. You can see that
it &lt;a href="https://jon.io"&gt;Jon.IO&lt;/a&gt; doesn't look like the standard Pelican installation but it uses most of the nifty plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tailwind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No idea why but my (first) new version was not using tailwind and that was stupid. What you see here was built in less than a day and it is exactly how I want it to be - web and mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Continuous deployment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously. Commiting to the master branch on Github, triggers a Github hook and the new article (which is written in Markdown) is posted.
The RSS feed is updated and SendFox sends automatically an email to the mailing list (depending on the category).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enough with the stupid flexing. Is it opensource?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously. Go and fork here,  &lt;a href="pages/weekly-tips"&gt;sign up to the mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and ping me if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Next: Building the best platform (on the planet) for courses using Google Cloud, Flask and TensorFlow &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>The #RoamCult: Why creating a cult for your Startups is what you should be doing right now</title><link href="http://jon.io/the-roamcult-why-creating-a-cult-for-your-startups-is-what-you-should-be-doing-right-now" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-11T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-07-11:/the-roamcult-why-creating-a-cult-for-your-startups-is-what-you-should-be-doing-right-now</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or why you should have a "Believer" plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recurring revenue. Two words synonym to predictable revenue and known for bringing smiles and high-fives to VCs and founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single tech company I know has a recurring revenue business model. Even the big ones are trying moving to a SaaS model …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or why you should have a "Believer" plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recurring revenue. Two words synonym to predictable revenue and known for bringing smiles and high-fives to VCs and founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single tech company I know has a recurring revenue business model. Even the big ones are trying moving to a SaaS model by becoming Cloud-first/ready or whatever bullshit (come on it is 2020 already).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe there is a new business model. The Believer model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Roam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out about &lt;a href="https://roamresearch.com/"&gt;Roam&lt;/a&gt; a couple weeks ago - a company that created a ton of buzz with their #roamcult and having a “Believers” plan. This is not an advertisement of the product and I am not an investor at Roam. But I am a believer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of paying $15 per month or $165 per year, how about you pay $500 for &lt;strong&gt;five years&lt;/strong&gt;? One of the pros is of course the 40% discount but what about the cons?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Will the company still existing in five years? This is a brand new startup after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/ Having access to brand new features before anyone else is cool but is it that cool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very interesting business model and definitely could spark a new trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Believers: Building your “cult”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some products that are epic. People love them. They just love them. They are irrationally obsessed with them. These are the believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believers are the people that if you had a heavy metal band, they &lt;a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-news/metallica-drive-in-shows-1041638/"&gt;will travel 5 hours to see you performing a pre-recorded show in a drive-in&lt;/a&gt;. These people have a deep connection with your product and they get the maximum value out of it. It might even be part of their identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can you identify your believers and how to give them incentives them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding your Believers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I built a Startup, there were some users that were a pain in the ass. Non-stop questions and criticism on a daily basis. My team has asked me giving them a refund and be done with it. But&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You never let your believers get away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People that engage like crazy with your product/brand and are vocal, are your believers. Or your haters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believers and haters are separated by a thin line called &lt;strong&gt;constructive feedback&lt;/strong&gt;. Learn how to recognize the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to find your believers is by talking non-stop to your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending an email every month doesn’t cut it. Keep them in the loop with webinars, twitch broadcasts, previews of new features, asking for feedback etc. The believers are the people that log in the most and engage the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rewarding believers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An epic idea is something that Roam did with their “cult”. They gave the opportunity to their believers participate in the financial round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/roam.PNG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all of your struggling to raise money, consider this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Startup is giving the opportunity to its users to participate in the round. Not only the product is awesome, not only there are customers using it, there are users that love it so much that want to be with you for the long run. People knock on your door to give you money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty good scenario for fund raising in my book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Isn’t this like a one-time-fee thingy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. It is more about the money. It’s always been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A product is the sum of the value it provides and the emotional connection that has with its users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking that you can just add one plan in your pricing page and people will flock and turn into believers is naive. Oh sorry, it is not naive. It is actually stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a fan base/cult/believer requires that the company is transparent and let’s everyone (that wants to) participate in the decision making. In my opinion there hasn’t been enough innovation in pricing models and more experiments should be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows. Maybe you can try creating your own cult and find new ways to make people connect with your company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@alicekat?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Alice Donovan Rouse&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/roam?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>Win in every negotiation</title><link href="http://jon.io/win-in-every-negotiation" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-25T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-05-25:/win-in-every-negotiation</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons in Information Asymmetry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to San Francisco, I didn’t have a car. Who needs a car in San Francisco? And the parking is like $350 per month so that is a hard no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sadly because I had a Startup, I had to go to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons in Information Asymmetry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to San Francisco, I didn’t have a car. Who needs a car in San Francisco? And the parking is like $350 per month so that is a hard no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sadly because I had a Startup, I had to go to Palo Alto, Mountain View, Oakland for meetings and events. That meant that I had to rent a car or waste hours on public transportation and Uber/Lyft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Startup that never raised money from a VC, I knew we had to rent a car but our budget was best case $1200 per month. That’s $66 per day, including insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Welcome to Information Asymmetry.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information asymmetry is a fancy word of saying “I know something that you don’t”. You can use that when you negotiate for a job, with customers, with sales people and you girlfriend/wife when it is time to do the dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first step, we need to identify our &lt;strong&gt;informational advantage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The informational advantage I had was the length of the rent. 30 days is not usual. I decided to go with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to rent a car, the typical conversation goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I would like a car from that date to that date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I see, we have this model and that model for $12 more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking for the cheaper option&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got it, that is $100 per day plus insurance, plus taxes for 3 days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using information asymmetry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I would like a car for three days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I see, we have this model and that model for $4 more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, what is the price for the cheaper model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That will be $100 per day plus insurance, plus taxes for three days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it is roughly $100 per day, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is correct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we do something better if I wanted the car for a week?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could do $95 if it is for week&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing! Thank you a lot. You know what, if we can do something better in terms of pricing, I could go for three weeks as I don’t want to bring the car back again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see. The best I can do if you go for a whole month is $90&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you! That is perfect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we used information asymmetry was by &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; revealing all the information we had in one go but in a &lt;strong&gt;dripping style&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can it work when you negotiate your salary? Of course it can!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to gather as much information as you can before going for an interview. That means knowing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average salary for that position&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average salary for that position in &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other possible perks (extra stocks, more vacation days)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without this information, we are in an informational disadvantage as we have no idea whether the salary that we want is &lt;strong&gt;even feasible&lt;/strong&gt; for that company. Yes, an engineer can make $350k in a public tech company but in a small Startup that is doubtful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my whole professional career, I managed to get &lt;strong&gt;way more&lt;/strong&gt; than any other of my peers in terms of salary, bonuses, stocks and vacation days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming up next: Information Asymmetry to negotiate a raise&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>Marie Kondo your Startup</title><link href="http://jon.io/marie-kondo-your-startup" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-17T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-05-17:/marie-kondo-your-startup</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself if it sparks revenue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I am the person that has 53 different hobbies and is good at three of them. And I don’t plan changing any time soon as I subscribe to the &lt;a href="jack-of-many-trades-master-of-anything.html"&gt;Jack of many trades, Master of Anything …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself if it sparks revenue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I am the person that has 53 different hobbies and is good at three of them. And I don’t plan changing any time soon as I subscribe to the &lt;a href="jack-of-many-trades-master-of-anything.html"&gt;Jack of many trades, Master of Anything&lt;/a&gt; theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I am like a hoarder that finds “joy” in everything. Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Startups, I have to be more intentional. I don’t use the word “focused” because this term is used by people that have one brain cell and cannot do more than two things at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eliminating the unnecessary&lt;/strong&gt; is the most critical skill in a Startup and companies folded in just two weeks after Corona Virus started because they were on a “hiring spree, renting bigger offices” instead of “focusing”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can Marie Kondo give us some tips?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The KonMari rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KonMari method has six rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commit yourself to tidying up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine your ideal lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finish discarding first. Before getting rid of items, sincerely thank each item for serving its purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tidy by category, not location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the right order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself it it sparks joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s “Silicon Valey” these rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1/ Clean up your business data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Commit yourself to tidying up” is the best advice for getting all your data in one place. If you don’t know how things are, how do you know what to improve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goals in Google Analytics that no-one is checking out? Clean them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That Instagram account that you keep posting but you don’t track any conversions? Goodbye!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2/ Imaging your ideal “exit”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to build a business that makes tons of revenue? Is this an acquihire game so you don’t really need a lot of customers? Do you want to raise money and work hard to keep VCs happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about your future. “Imagine your ideal lifestyle”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3/ Firing before hiring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be pretty obvious but 99% of VC-funded companies seem to have no idea how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before randomly hiring people and celebrating your “headcount”, ask if every single employee provides value to your mission. More employees that you just hired to satisfy your investors means more stress on your financials, slower product development, more red tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t hire 100 engineers. Hire ten 10x engineers (yes, I hate that term too, just play along).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marie said it loud and clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finish discarding first. Before getting rid of items, sincerely thank each item for serving its purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would add that you might want to give something more than just a thank you for your service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4/ Hire the best: Location is irrelevant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, I got the “Tidy by category, not location” and I opened it up a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote in the past about &lt;a href="why-i-love-working-remotely-and-why-your-company-cannot-and-never-will.html"&gt;working remotely&lt;/a&gt; and if you company STILL doesn’t allow remote working I can assume that you are running a coffee place or a restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5/ Follow the right order&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are “cleaning up” your company, you should prioritize customers/sales, support, product development and then anything else. Nothing else should matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you taking the whole company to Tahoe this winter? Awesome. Make sure that everything else is in place first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6/ Ask yourself if it sparks revenue/value&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you are doing needs to have only one goal: revenue (or adding value to customers). No-one cares about a better looking website. Or about using the latest in backend technology. Or that you have 34303403011 employees in 232 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOES IT MAKE MONEY?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not, MarieKondo it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>How to try your Startup idea with $0</title><link href="http://jon.io/how-to-try-your-startup-idea-with-0" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-09T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2020-05-09:/how-to-try-your-startup-idea-with-0</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago I was teaching a small course at Stanford about Entrepreneurship and I remember the &lt;strong&gt;number one&lt;/strong&gt; question was how to raise money.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tell you the truth, I was surprised because the most important question someone that wants to start a business should ask is how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago I was teaching a small course at Stanford about Entrepreneurship and I remember the &lt;strong&gt;number one&lt;/strong&gt; question was how to raise money.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tell you the truth, I was surprised because the most important question someone that wants to start a business should ask is how to make a product that people want. Anything else is details. Short of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the exercises we had, was to think of a product that could generate $1 per month. If you think that is easy, I challenge you to try it out. It requires a pretty good amount of thinking and planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limitations we had were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have one day to prepare&lt;/strong&gt;. That means no overthinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You cannot spend any money (no ads)&lt;/strong&gt;. You have to use your existing network (friend, family, social networks)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You cannot use any external resources&lt;/strong&gt;. Getting creative or learning some basic building (and selling) skills is something you need to do if you want to run a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you had all this in place, you had to pitch your idea to the whole class. Who knows, you might get some subscribers for your idea on the spot (hint: no one did but it is a good exercise treating everyone as a potential customer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw at least 30 different ideas that managed to make $1 to $250 recurring monthly revenue and to tell you the truth, it blew my mind. But more importantly it blew &lt;strong&gt;THEIR&lt;/strong&gt; mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We proved that you don’t need a lot of money, huge infrastructure and 10 people to try out an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who are wondering, the next step was to “build a company” that makes $1,000 per month then $10,000 and finally $1,000,000 per month. That way we could talk about &lt;strong&gt;finding a co-founder&lt;/strong&gt;, talk about &lt;strong&gt;funding&lt;/strong&gt; and how and when &lt;strong&gt;to scale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning more, I plan to post on a weekly basis my “how to Startup” so just &lt;a href="pages/weekly-tips"&gt;follow along&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now back to making money from zero money. My favorite subject. 👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by picking up an idea. We want something that might generate at least $1 per month. Write that idea down and place it as background in your phone. Like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by picking up an idea. We want something that might generate at least $1 per month. Write that idea down and place it as background in your phone. Like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mario" src="/images/mario.png"&gt;
I used Instagram to make this, so don't judge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some ideas to get your creative juices flowing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram retouch service&lt;/strong&gt;. Retouch all photos that someone posts on social media. I know a friend that makes $1500 per month just for light retouching. I even paid $10 on reddit to have this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="jonking" src="/images/jonking.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Websites&lt;/strong&gt;. Do you know how to setup Squarespace? Or Wix? Or Wordpress? If not, you should. It is very easy. Charge for management fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online talent company&lt;/strong&gt;. It will sound silly but there many influencers on YouTube/Instagram/TikTok that have decent traffic and no idea how to monetize it. They will LOVE a manager to handle this. Leave a comment below if you want to learn more about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this exercise is not to make money and retire in a Greek Island. It is to understand how sales and marketing works and making something that people want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you found your idea, time to get some customers and validate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You start with your friends, family and expand to your social media. After that you go on Reddit, Craigslist, your local newspaper and Nextdoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you fantasize that you could do it, &lt;strong&gt;stop right now&lt;/strong&gt; and actually do it. And then send me your a screenshot of your hustle and &lt;strong&gt;I’ll be the first person to send you $1 via Venmo&lt;/strong&gt;. No bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I love working remotely (and why your company cannot and never will)</title><link href="http://jon.io/why-i-love-working-remotely-and-why-your-company-cannot-and-never-will" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-18T10:48:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-22T02:24:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Jon V &lt;h2&gt;BigData. Startups. Trading.&lt;/h2&gt;</name></author><id>tag:jon.io,2018-10-18:/why-i-love-working-remotely-and-why-your-company-cannot-and-never-will</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is 4pm in Italy and I just had an epic pizza. Yes, not a slice but a whole pizza. Don’t judge, this is my lunch and I have a long day/night ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 9am in California and usually around that time, companies are ready to have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is 4pm in Italy and I just had an epic pizza. Yes, not a slice but a whole pizza. Don’t judge, this is my lunch and I have a long day/night ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 9am in California and usually around that time, companies are ready to have their Standup where everyone talks for less than 10 seconds and says what was done yesterday, what needs to be done today and if there are any show-stoppers. In our case, everyone is working from another state (or country) and I can assure you it takes us waaay longer than 10 seconds. Waaaaaay longer. Not because we are apart but because we like to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am logging in today from Italy and the internet in this Airbnb keeps dropping all the time. And I feel a bit sleepy which is definitely the jet-lag and not the pizza. Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being on my fourth Startup, I kinda know how not to annoy everybody with my stuttering voice so I have Google Fi and it works pretty good. Most of the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Google Fi for the rescue" src="/images/googlefi.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for my co-founder Niko that has strategically selected the best noise-to-work-to-view place at a coffee place in New York (it is lunch time for him), Maria in Salt Lake City that is doing some upgrades in her house while showing us our new epic homepage (and her new patio), Rania grilling us (mostly me) for not having compliance approved any blog posts (ha, add this to the list!) while she is about to put the kids to sleep (is it 7pm in Athens/ Greece), Alex trying to fight off his food cravings by entering a meditative state through product development (three more hours to breaks his intermitting fasting in Los Angeles) and more people jumping on and off or reporting on Slack. Good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some of us it is the beginning of the working day, for others the middle or the end which makes things tricky to plan. Oh and some people are on vacations (we have an unlimited vacations policy). Did I say good times? Good times again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having lived in this environment for almost ten years and a half version of it at Splunk which acquired my last company, I can tell you why this is the best way to work. The healthiest and the happiest. And then I can tell you why your company cannot do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why we can do it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this to work, the whole team needs to be aligned. Needs to be aware that “working from everywhere” means that you need to make sure you have stable internet connection, no noise and that you can work concentrated. We cannot have someone that needs to be (micro)managed. You need to be self-motivated. And you need to be really good at what you are doing. Reeeeaally good. You need to be an one-army man/woman. But the reward is that you get to have pizza while building products and having fun with a view like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why your company sucks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startups used to be about working from a garage with a team of super dedicated and smart engineers. They were makers. Creators. They could work all day/night and they would radiate passion and will inspire people to join them. Not only for the perks. Not only or the salary. But mostly for the vision.
I know that you are thinking “hey man, we need to pay bills and you cannot buy medical insurance with passion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correct. But if you want to evolve as an employee (and as a person?), you need to demand more than just a simple transaction of “money &amp;lt;&amp;gt; time”: Someone gives you money, you give back your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, let me give you an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built AgentRisk to help Entrepreneurs manage their money better. More transparently. We even provide free education for cryptocurrencies. &lt;strong&gt;No this is not a product pitch&lt;/strong&gt;. What I am trying to say is that every single customer we have, was an employee at some point and then became &lt;strong&gt;obsessed with a problem&lt;/strong&gt;. They worked like there is no tomorrow, failed, tried again, failed, tried again and then made it. They freaking made it. And I am not saying that they just made money. They are better, more rounded as a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is the reason why your company cannot let you work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies hire people that don’t have passion. That don’t have vision. They need you to work 9–5 at an office so that a manager can nano-manage you. Vacations are not unlimited because they think you will be on vacations all the time. And of course you end up wasting time and time and time again in meetings (ok some companies are not like that but you get my point).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at least you get to pay the bills, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What you can do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working remotely is not for everyone obviously and not everyone is a super engineer. The truth is in the middle and companies just don’t know how to run remote teams. It takes time and dedication and many times I prefer being with the whole team at an office (we fly all together in one place) than on Google Hangouts. But working from wherever you want, is liberating. And the pizza is not bad at all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Startups"></category></entry></feed>